<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-2219/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_12">
        <num>Chapter 59-12</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_12_2219">
          <num>59-12-2219</num>
          <heading>County option sales and use tax for highways and public transit -- Base -- Rate -- Distribution and expenditure of revenue -- Revenue may not supplant existing budgeted transportation revenue.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 7/1/2025
59-12-2219.
County option sales and use tax for highways and public transit -- Base -- Rate -- Distribution and expenditure of revenue -- Revenue may not supplant existing budgeted transportation revenue.
(1)
Subject to the other provisions of this part, and subject to Subsection
(13)
, a county legislative body may impose a sales and use tax of .25% on the transactions described in Subsection
59-12-103(1)
within the county, including the cities and towns within the county.
(2)
Subject to Subsection
(9)
, the commission shall distribute sales and use tax revenue collected under this section as provided in Subsections
(3)
through
(8)
.
(3)
After application of Subsection
59-12-2206(5)
, if the entire boundary of a county that imposes a sales and use tax under this section is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:
(a)
.10% shall be transferred to the public transit district in accordance with Section
59-12-2206
;
(b)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(c)
.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.
(4)
If the entire boundary of a county that imposes a sales and use tax under this section is not annexed into a single public transit district, but a city or town within the county is annexed into a single large public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:
(a)
for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that city or town as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be transferred to the public transit district in accordance with Section
59-12-2206
;
(ii)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(iii)
.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body;
(b)
for an eligible political subdivision within the county, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that eligible political subdivision as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be transferred to the eligible political subdivision in accordance with Section
59-12-2206
;
(ii)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(iii)
.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body; and
(c)
the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue, except for the sales and use tax revenue described in Subsections
(4)(a)
and
(b)
, as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(ii)
.15% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.
(5)
For a county not described in Subsection
(3)
or
(4)
, if a county of the second, third, fourth, fifth, or sixth class imposes a sales and use tax under this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:
(a)
for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that city or town as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
;
(ii)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(7)
; and
(iii)
.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body;
(b)
for an eligible political subdivision within the county, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that eligible political subdivision as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
;
(ii)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(7)
; and
(iii)
.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body; and
(c)
the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue, except for the sales and use tax revenue described in Subsections
(5)(a)
and
(b)
, as follows:
(i)
.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(ii)
.15% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.
(6)
(a)
Subject to Subsection
(6)(b)
, the commission shall make the distributions required by Subsections
(3)(b)
, (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) as follows:
(i)
50% of the total revenue collected under Subsections
(3)(b)
, (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) within the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section shall be distributed to the unincorporated areas, cities, and towns within those counties and cities on the basis of the percentage that the population of each unincorporated area, city, or town bears to the total population of all of the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section; and
(ii)
50% of the total revenue collected under Subsections
(3)(b)
, (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) within the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section shall be distributed to the unincorporated areas, cities, and towns within those counties and cities on the basis of the location of the transaction as determined under Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
.
(b)
(i)
Population for purposes of this Subsection
(6)
shall be based on, to the extent not otherwise required by federal law:
(A)
the most recent estimate from the Utah Population Committee created in Section
63C-20-103
; or
(B)
if the Utah Population Committee estimate is not available for each municipality and unincorporated area, the adjusted sub-county population estimate provided by the Utah Population Committee in accordance with Section
63C-20-104
.
(ii)
If a needed population estimate is not available from the United States Bureau of the Census, population figures shall be derived from an estimate from the Utah Population Committee.
(7)
(a)
(i)
Subject to the requirements in Subsections
(7)(b)
and
(c)
, a county legislative body:
(A)
for a county that obtained approval from a majority of the county's registered voters voting on the imposition of a sales and use tax under this section prior to May 10, 2016, may, in consultation with any cities, towns, or eligible political subdivisions within the county, and in compliance with the requirements for changing an allocation under Subsection
(7)(e)
, allocate the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
by adopting a resolution specifying the percentage of revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
that will be allocated to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision; or
(B)
for a county that imposes a sales and use tax under this section on or after May 10, 2016, shall, in consultation with any cities, towns, or eligible political subdivisions within the county, allocate the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
by adopting a resolution specifying the percentage of revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
that will be allocated to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision.
(ii)
If a county described in Subsection
(7)(a)(i)(A)
does not allocate the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
in accordance with Subsection
(7)(a)(i)(A)
, the commission shall distribute 100% of the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
to:
(A)
a public transit district for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district; or
(B)
an eligible political subdivision within the county.
(b)
If a county legislative body allocates the revenue as described in Subsection
(7)(a)(i)
, the county legislative body shall allocate not less than 25% of the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
to:
(i)
a public transit district for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district; or
(ii)
an eligible political subdivision within the county.
(c)
Notwithstanding Section
59-12-2208
, the opinion question described in Section
59-12-2208
shall state the allocations the county legislative body makes in accordance with this Subsection
(7)
.
(d)
The commission shall make the distributions required by Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
as follows:
(i)
the percentage specified by a county legislative body shall be distributed in accordance with a resolution adopted by a county legislative body under Subsection
(7)(a)
to an eligible political subdivision or a public transit district within the county; and
(ii)
except as provided in Subsection
(7)(a)(ii)
, if a county legislative body allocates less than 100% of the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision, the remainder of the revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
not allocated by a county legislative body through a resolution under Subsection
(7)(a)
shall be distributed as follows:
(A)
50% of the revenue as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(B)
50% of the revenue to the county legislative body.
(e)
If a county legislative body seeks to change an allocation specified in a resolution under Subsection
(7)(a)
, the county legislative body may change the allocation by:
(i)
adopting a resolution in accordance with Subsection
(7)(a)
specifying the percentage of revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
that will be allocated to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision;
(ii)
obtaining approval to change the allocation of the sales and use tax by a majority of all the members of the county legislative body; and
(iii)
subject to Subsection
(7)(f)
:
(A)
in accordance with Section
59-12-2208
, submitting an opinion question to the county's registered voters voting on changing the allocation so that each registered voter has the opportunity to express the registered voter's opinion on whether the allocation should be changed; and
(B)
in accordance with Section
59-12-2208
, obtaining approval to change the allocation from a majority of the county's registered voters voting on changing the allocation.
(f)
Notwithstanding Section
59-12-2208
, the opinion question required by Subsection
(7)(e)(iii)(A)
shall state the allocations specified in the resolution adopted in accordance with Subsection
(7)(e)
and approved by the county legislative body in accordance with Subsection
(7)(e)(ii)
.
(g)
(i)
If a county makes an allocation by adopting a resolution under Subsection
(7)(a)
or changes an allocation by adopting a resolution under Subsection
(7)(e)
, the allocation shall take effect on the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice meeting the requirements of Subsection
(7)(g)(ii)
from the county.
(ii)
The notice described in Subsection
(7)(g)(i)
shall state:
(A)
that the county will make or change the percentage of an allocation under Subsection
(7)(a)
or
(e)
; and
(B)
the percentage of revenue under Subsection
(5)(a)(ii)
or
(5)(b)(ii)
that will be allocated to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision.
(8)
(a)
If a public transit district is organized after the date a county legislative body first imposes a tax under this section, a change in a distribution required by this section may not take effect until the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice from the public transit district of the organization of the public transit district.
(b)
If an eligible political subdivision intends to provide public transit service within a county after the date a county legislative body first imposes a tax under this section, a change in a distribution required by this section may not take effect until the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice from the eligible political subdivision stating that the eligible political subdivision intends to provide public transit service within the county.
(9)
(a)
(i)
Notwithstanding Subsections
(3)
through
(8)
, for a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before May 8, 2018, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, the commission shall distribute all of the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county before June 30, 2019, to the county for the purposes described in Subsection
(9)(a)(ii)
.
(ii)
For any revenue collected by a county pursuant to Subsection
(9)(a)(i)
before June 30, 2019, the county may expend that revenue for:
(A)
reducing transportation related debt;
(B)
a regionally significant transportation facility; or
(C)
a public transit project of regional significance.
(b)
For a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before May 8, 2018, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county on or after July 1, 2019, as described in Subsections
(3)
through
(8)
.
(c)
For a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, if the entire boundary of that county is annexed into a large public transit district, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2019, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county as described in Subsections
(3)
through
(8)
.
(10)
(a)
Except as provided in Subsection
(10)(b)
, a county, city, or town may expend revenue collected from a tax under this section, except for revenue the commission distributes in accordance with Subsection
(3)(a)
, (4)(a)(i), (4)(b)(i), or (7)(d)(i), for a purpose described in Section
59-12-2212.2
.
(b)
In addition to the uses permitted in Subsection
(10)(a)
, a county of the first class may transfer the portion allocated to the county under this section to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section
17D-4-202.1
for revitalization of a convention center owned by the county within a city of the first class and surrounding revitalization projects related to the convention center.
(11)
(a)
A public transit district or an eligible political subdivision may expend revenue the commission distributes in accordance with Subsection
(3)(a)
, (4)(a)(i), (4)(b)(i), or (7)(d)(i) for capital expenses and service delivery expenses of the public transit district or eligible political subdivision.
(b)
As provided in Section
59-12-2212.2
, for the .10% designated for public transit described in Subsection
(3)(a)
that is not contractually obligated for debt service, beginning on July 1, 2026, a public transit district shall make available to the Department of Transportation an amount equal to 10% of the .10% to be used for public transit innovation grants as provided in Title 72, Chapter 2, Part 4, Public Transit Innovation Grants.
(12)
Notwithstanding Section
59-12-2208
, a county, city, or town legislative body may, but is not required to, submit an opinion question to the county's, city's, or town's registered voters in accordance with Section
59-12-2208
to impose a sales and use tax under this section.
(13)
(a)
(i)
Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, if the entire boundary of a county is annexed into a large public transit district, if the county legislative body wishes to impose a sales and use tax under this section, the county legislative body shall pass the ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or before June 30, 2022.
(ii)
If the entire boundary of a county is annexed into a large public transit district, the county legislative body may not pass an ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2022.
(b)
Notwithstanding the deadline described in Subsection
(13)(a)
, any sales and use tax imposed under this section by passage of a county ordinance on or before June 30, 2022, may remain in effect.
(14)
(a)
Beginning on July 1, 2020, and subject to Subsection
(15)
, if a county has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section, subject to the provisions of this part, the legislative body of a city or town described in Subsection
(14)(b)
may impose a .25% sales and use tax on the transactions described in Subsection
59-12-103(1)
within the city or town.
(b)
The following cities or towns may impose a sales and use tax described in Subsection
(14)(a)
:
(i)
a city or town that has been annexed into a public transit district; or
(ii)
an eligible political subdivision.
(c)
If a city or town imposes a sales and use tax as provided in this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the city or town as follows:
(i)
.125% to the city or town that imposed the sales and use tax, to be distributed as provided in Subsection
(6)
; and
(ii)
.125%, as applicable, to:
(A)
the public transit district in which the city or town is annexed; or
(B)
the eligible political subdivision for public transit services.
(d)
If a city or town imposes a sales and use tax under this section and the county subsequently imposes a sales and use tax under this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the city or town as described in Subsection
(14)(c)
.
(15)
(a)
(i)
Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, if a city or town legislative body wishes to impose a sales and use tax under this section, the city or town legislative body shall pass the ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or before June 30, 2022.
(ii)
A city or town legislative body may not pass an ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2022.
(b)
Notwithstanding the deadline described in Subsection
(15)(a)
, any sales and use tax imposed under this section by passage of an ordinance by a city or town legislative body on or before June 30, 2022, may remain in effect.
Amended by Chapter
400
, 2025 General Session</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the other provisions of this part, and subject to Subsection , a county legislative body may impose a sales and use tax of .25% on the transactions described in Subsection within the county, including the cities and towns within the county.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to Subsection , the commission shall distribute sales and use tax revenue collected under this section as provided in Subsections through .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>After application of Subsection , if the entire boundary of a county that imposes a sales and use tax under this section is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_3__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>.10% shall be transferred to the public transit district in accordance with Section ;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_3__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If the entire boundary of a county that imposes a sales and use tax under this section is not annexed into a single public transit district, but a city or town within the county is annexed into a single large public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that city or town as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be transferred to the public transit district in accordance with Section ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for an eligible political subdivision within the county, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that eligible political subdivision as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be transferred to the eligible political subdivision in accordance with Section ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue, except for the sales and use tax revenue described in Subsections and , as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_4__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.15% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a county not described in Subsection or , if a county of the second, third, fourth, fifth, or sixth class imposes a sales and use tax under this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the county as follows:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that city or town as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>for an eligible political subdivision within the county, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within that eligible political subdivision as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.05% shall be distributed to the county legislative body; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue, except for the sales and use tax revenue described in Subsections and , as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.10% shall be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.15% shall be distributed to the county legislative body.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsection , the commission shall make the distributions required by Subsections , (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>50% of the total revenue collected under Subsections , (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) within the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section shall be distributed to the unincorporated areas, cities, and towns within those counties and cities on the basis of the percentage that the population of each unincorporated area, city, or town bears to the total population of all of the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>50% of the total revenue collected under Subsections , (4)(a)(ii), (4)(b)(ii), (4)(c)(i), (5)(a)(i), (5)(b)(i), (5)(c)(i), and (7)(d)(ii)(A) within the counties and cities that impose a tax under this section shall be distributed to the unincorporated areas, cities, and towns within those counties and cities on the basis of the location of the transaction as determined under Sections through .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Population for purposes of this Subsection shall be based on, to the extent not otherwise required by federal law:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_6__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a needed population estimate is not available from the United States Bureau of the Census, population figures shall be derived from an estimate from the Utah Population Committee.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to the requirements in Subsections and , a county legislative body:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a county described in Subsection does not allocate the revenue under Subsection or in accordance with Subsection , the commission shall distribute 100% of the revenue under Subsection or to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a county legislative body allocates the revenue as described in Subsection , the county legislative body shall allocate not less than 25% of the revenue under Subsection or to:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a public transit district for a city or town within the county that is annexed into a single public transit district; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an eligible political subdivision within the county.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Section , the opinion question described in Section shall state the allocations the county legislative body makes in accordance with this Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall make the distributions required by Subsection or as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the percentage specified by a county legislative body shall be distributed in accordance with a resolution adopted by a county legislative body under Subsection to an eligible political subdivision or a public transit district within the county; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>except as provided in Subsection , if a county legislative body allocates less than 100% of the revenue under Subsection or to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision, the remainder of the revenue under Subsection or not allocated by a county legislative body through a resolution under Subsection shall be distributed as follows:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a county legislative body seeks to change an allocation specified in a resolution under Subsection , the county legislative body may change the allocation by:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>adopting a resolution in accordance with Subsection specifying the percentage of revenue under Subsection or that will be allocated to a public transit district or an eligible political subdivision;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>obtaining approval to change the allocation of the sales and use tax by a majority of all the members of the county legislative body; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_e__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>subject to Subsection :</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Section , the opinion question required by Subsection shall state the allocations specified in the resolution adopted in accordance with Subsection and approved by the county legislative body in accordance with Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a county makes an allocation by adopting a resolution under Subsection or changes an allocation by adopting a resolution under Subsection , the allocation shall take effect on the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice meeting the requirements of Subsection from the county.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_7__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The notice described in Subsection shall state:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_8__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a public transit district is organized after the date a county legislative body first imposes a tax under this section, a change in a distribution required by this section may not take effect until the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice from the public transit district of the organization of the public transit district.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_8__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If an eligible political subdivision intends to provide public transit service within a county after the date a county legislative body first imposes a tax under this section, a change in a distribution required by this section may not take effect until the first distribution the commission makes under this section after a 90-day period that begins on the date the commission receives written notice from the eligible political subdivision stating that the eligible political subdivision intends to provide public transit service within the county.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding Subsections through , for a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before May 8, 2018, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, the commission shall distribute all of the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county before June 30, 2019, to the county for the purposes described in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For any revenue collected by a county pursuant to Subsection before June 30, 2019, the county may expend that revenue for:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before May 8, 2018, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county on or after July 1, 2019, as described in Subsections through .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_9__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a county that has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section before June 30, 2019, if the entire boundary of that county is annexed into a large public transit district, and if the county imposes a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2019, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the county as described in Subsections through .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_10__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a county, city, or town may expend revenue collected from a tax under this section, except for revenue the commission distributes in accordance with Subsection , (4)(a)(i), (4)(b)(i), or (7)(d)(i), for a purpose described in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_10__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>In addition to the uses permitted in Subsection , a county of the first class may transfer the portion allocated to the county under this section to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section for revitalization of a convention center owned by the county within a city of the first class and surrounding revitalization projects related to the convention center.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_11__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A public transit district or an eligible political subdivision may expend revenue the commission distributes in accordance with Subsection , (4)(a)(i), (4)(b)(i), or (7)(d)(i) for capital expenses and service delivery expenses of the public transit district or eligible political subdivision.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_11__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>As provided in Section , for the .10% designated for public transit described in Subsection that is not contractually obligated for debt service, beginning on July 1, 2026, a public transit district shall make available to the Department of Transportation an amount equal to 10% of the .10% to be used for public transit innovation grants as provided in Title 72, Chapter 2, Part 4, Public Transit Innovation Grants.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Section , a county, city, or town legislative body may, but is not required to, submit an opinion question to the county's, city's, or town's registered voters in accordance with Section to impose a sales and use tax under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_13__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_13__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, if the entire boundary of a county is annexed into a large public transit district, if the county legislative body wishes to impose a sales and use tax under this section, the county legislative body shall pass the ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or before June 30, 2022.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_13__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the entire boundary of a county is annexed into a large public transit district, the county legislative body may not pass an ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2022.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_13__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the deadline described in Subsection , any sales and use tax imposed under this section by passage of a county ordinance on or before June 30, 2022, may remain in effect.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Beginning on July 1, 2020, and subject to Subsection , if a county has not imposed a sales and use tax under this section, subject to the provisions of this part, the legislative body of a city or town described in Subsection may impose a .25% sales and use tax on the transactions described in Subsection within the city or town.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The following cities or towns may impose a sales and use tax described in Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a city or town that has been annexed into a public transit district; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an eligible political subdivision.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a city or town imposes a sales and use tax as provided in this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected by the city or town as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.125% to the city or town that imposed the sales and use tax, to be distributed as provided in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.125%, as applicable, to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_14__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a city or town imposes a sales and use tax under this section and the county subsequently imposes a sales and use tax under this section, the commission shall distribute the sales and use tax revenue collected within the city or town as described in Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_2219__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_15__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_15__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding any other provision in this section, if a city or town legislative body wishes to impose a sales and use tax under this section, the city or town legislative body shall pass the ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or before June 30, 2022.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_15__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A city or town legislative body may not pass an ordinance to impose a sales and use tax under this section on or after July 1, 2022.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_2219__subsec_15__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding the deadline described in Subsection , any sales and use tax imposed under this section by passage of an ordinance by a city or town legislative body on or before June 30, 2022, may remain in effect.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
