<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-103/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_12">
        <num>Chapter 59-12</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_12_103">
          <num>59-12-103</num>
          <heading>Superseded 1/1/2026</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 7/1/2025
Superseded 1/1/2026
59-12-103.
Sales and use tax base -- Rates -- Effective dates -- Use of sales and use tax revenue.
(1)
A tax is imposed on the purchaser as provided in this part on the purchase price or sales price for amounts paid or charged for the following transactions:
(a)
retail sales of tangible personal property made within the state;
(b)
amounts paid for:
(i)
telecommunications service, other than mobile telecommunications service, that originates and terminates within the boundaries of this state;
(ii)
mobile telecommunications service that originates and terminates within the boundaries of one state only to the extent permitted by the Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act, 4 U.S.C. Sec. 116 et seq.; or
(iii)
an ancillary service associated with a:
(A)
telecommunications service described in Subsection
(1)(b)(i)
; or
(B)
mobile telecommunications service described in Subsection
(1)(b)(ii)
;
(c)
sales of the following for commercial use:
(i)
gas;
(ii)
electricity;
(iii)
heat;
(iv)
coal;
(v)
fuel oil; or
(vi)
other fuels;
(d)
sales of the following for residential use:
(i)
gas;
(ii)
electricity;
(iii)
heat;
(iv)
coal;
(v)
fuel oil; or
(vi)
other fuels;
(e)
sales of prepared food;
(f)
except as provided in Section
59-12-104
, amounts paid or charged as admission or user fees for theaters, movies, operas, museums, planetariums, shows of any type or nature, exhibitions, concerts, carnivals, amusement parks, amusement rides, circuses, menageries, fairs, races, contests, sporting events, dances, boxing matches, wrestling matches, closed circuit television broadcasts, billiard parlors, pool parlors, bowling lanes, golf, miniature golf, golf driving ranges, batting cages, skating rinks, ski lifts, ski runs, ski trails, snowmobile trails, tennis courts, swimming pools, water slides, river runs, jeep tours, boat tours, scenic cruises, horseback rides, sports activities, or any other amusement, entertainment, recreation, exhibition, cultural, or athletic activity;
(g)
amounts paid or charged for services for repairs or renovations of tangible personal property, unless Section
59-12-104
provides for an exemption from sales and use tax for:
(i)
the tangible personal property; and
(ii)
parts used in the repairs or renovations of the tangible personal property described in Subsection
(1)(g)(i)
, regardless of whether:
(A)
any parts are actually used in the repairs or renovations of that tangible personal property; or
(B)
the particular parts used in the repairs or renovations of that tangible personal property are exempt from a tax under this chapter;
(h)
except as provided in Subsection
59-12-104(7)
, amounts paid or charged for assisted cleaning or washing of tangible personal property;
(i)
amounts paid or charged for short-term rentals of tourist home, hotel, motel, or trailer court accommodations and services;
(j)
amounts paid or charged for laundry or dry cleaning services;
(k)
amounts paid or charged for leases or rentals of tangible personal property if within this state the tangible personal property is:
(i)
stored;
(ii)
used; or
(iii)
otherwise consumed;
(l)
amounts paid or charged for tangible personal property if within this state the tangible personal property is:
(i)
stored;
(ii)
used; or
(iii)
consumed;
(m)
amounts paid or charged for a sale:
(i)
(A)
of a product transferred electronically; or
(B)
of a repair or renovation of a product transferred electronically; and
(ii)
regardless of whether the sale provides:
(A)
a right of permanent use of the product; or
(B)
a right to use the product that is less than a permanent use, including a right:
(I)
for a definite or specified length of time; and
(II)
that terminates upon the occurrence of a condition; and
(n)
sales of leased tangible personal property from the lessor to the lessee made in the state.
(2)
(a)
Except as provided in Subsections
(2)(b)
through
(f)
, a state tax and a local tax are imposed on a transaction described in Subsection
(1)
equal to the sum of:
(i)
a state tax imposed on the transaction at a tax rate equal to the sum of:
(A)
4.70% plus the rate specified in Subsection
(11)(a)
; and
(B)
(I)
the tax rate the state imposes in accordance with Part 18, Additional State Sales and Use Tax Act, if the location of the transaction as determined under Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
is in a county in which the state imposes the tax under Part 18, Additional State Sales and Use Tax Act; and
(II)
the tax rate the state imposes in accordance with Part 20, Supplemental State Sales and Use Tax Act, if the location of the transaction as determined under Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
is in a city, town, or the unincorporated area of a county in which the state imposes the tax under Part 20, Supplemental State Sales and Use Tax Act; and
(ii)
a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the transaction under this chapter other than this part.
(b)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(f)
or
(g)
and subject to Subsection
(2)(l)
, a state tax and a local tax are imposed on a transaction described in Subsection
(1)(d)
equal to the sum of:
(i)
a state tax imposed on the transaction at a tax rate of 2%; and
(ii)
a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the transaction under this chapter other than this part.
(c)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(f)
or
(g)
, a state tax and a local tax are imposed on amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients equal to the sum of:
(i)
a state tax imposed on the amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients at a tax rate of 1.75%; and
(ii)
a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients under this chapter other than this part.
(d)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(f)
or (g), a state tax is imposed on amounts paid or charged for fuel to a common carrier that is a railroad for use in a locomotive engine at a rate of 4.85%.
(e)
(i)
(A)
If a shared vehicle owner certifies to the commission, on a form prescribed by the commission, that the shared vehicle is an individual-owned shared vehicle, a tax imposed under Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
does not apply to car sharing, a car-sharing program, a shared vehicle driver, or a shared vehicle owner.
(B)
A shared vehicle owner's certification described in Subsection
(2)(e)(i)(A)
is required once during the time that the shared vehicle owner owns the shared vehicle.
(C)
The commission shall verify that a shared vehicle is an individual-owned shared vehicle by verifying that the applicable Utah taxes imposed under this chapter were paid on the purchase of the shared vehicle.
(D)
The exception under Subsection
(2)(e)(i)(A)
applies to a certified individual-owned shared vehicle shared through a car-sharing program even if non-certified shared vehicles are also available to be shared through the same car-sharing program.
(ii)
A tax imposed under Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(B)
or
(2)(a)(ii)
applies to car sharing.
(iii)
(A)
A car-sharing program may rely in good faith on a shared vehicle owner's representation that the shared vehicle is an individual-owned shared vehicle certified with the commission as described in Subsection
(2)(e)(i)
.
(B)
If a car-sharing program relies in good faith on a shared vehicle owner's representation that the shared vehicle is an individual-owned shared vehicle certified with the commission as described in Subsection
(2)(e)(i)
, the car-sharing program is not liable for any tax, penalty, fee, or other sanction imposed on the shared vehicle owner.
(iv)
If all shared vehicles shared through a car-sharing program are certified as described in Subsection
(2)(e)(i)(A)
for a tax period, the car-sharing program has no obligation to collect and remit the tax under Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
for that tax period.
(v)
A car-sharing program is not required to list or otherwise identify an individual-owned shared vehicle on a return or an attachment to a return.
(vi)
A car-sharing program shall:
(A)
retain tax information for each car-sharing program transaction; and
(B)
provide the information described in Subsection
(2)(e)(vi)(A)
to the commission at the commission's request.
(f)
(i)
For a bundled transaction that is attributable to food and food ingredients and tangible personal property other than food and food ingredients, a state tax and a local tax is imposed on the entire bundled transaction equal to the sum of:
(A)
a state tax imposed on the entire bundled transaction equal to the sum of:
(I)
the tax rate described in Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
; and
(II)
(Aa)
the tax rate the state imposes in accordance with Part 18, Additional State Sales and Use Tax Act, if the location of the transaction as determined under Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
is in a county in which the state imposes the tax under Part 18, Additional State Sales and Use Tax Act; and
(Bb)
the tax rate the state imposes in accordance with Part 20, Supplemental State Sales and Use Tax Act, if the location of the transaction as determined under Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
is in a city, town, or the unincorporated area of a county in which the state imposes the tax under Part 20, Supplemental State Sales and Use Tax Act; and
(B)
a local tax imposed on the entire bundled transaction at the sum of the tax rates described in Subsection
(2)(a)(ii)
.
(ii)
If an optional computer software maintenance contract is a bundled transaction that consists of taxable and nontaxable products that are not separately itemized on an invoice or similar billing document, the purchase of the optional computer software maintenance contract is 40% taxable under this chapter and 60% nontaxable under this chapter.
(iii)
Subject to Subsection
(2)(f)(iv)
, for a bundled transaction other than a bundled transaction described in Subsection
(2)(f)(i)
or
(ii)
:
(A)
if the sales price of the bundled transaction is attributable to tangible personal property, a product, or a service that is subject to taxation under this chapter and tangible personal property, a product, or service that is not subject to taxation under this chapter, the entire bundled transaction is subject to taxation under this chapter unless:
(I)
the seller is able to identify by reasonable and verifiable standards the tangible personal property, product, or service that is not subject to taxation under this chapter from the books and records the seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business; or
(II)
state or federal law provides otherwise; or
(B)
if the sales price of a bundled transaction is attributable to two or more items of tangible personal property, products, or services that are subject to taxation under this chapter at different rates, the entire bundled transaction is subject to taxation under this chapter at the higher tax rate unless:
(I)
the seller is able to identify by reasonable and verifiable standards the tangible personal property, product, or service that is subject to taxation under this chapter at the lower tax rate from the books and records the seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business; or
(II)
state or federal law provides otherwise.
(iv)
For purposes of Subsection
(2)(f)(iii)
, books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.
(g)
(i)
Except as otherwise provided in this chapter and subject to Subsections
(2)(g)(ii)
and
(iii)
, if a transaction consists of the sale, lease, or rental of tangible personal property, a product, or a service that is subject to taxation under this chapter, and the sale, lease, or rental of tangible personal property, other property, a product, or a service that is not subject to taxation under this chapter, the entire transaction is subject to taxation under this chapter unless the seller, at the time of the transaction:
(A)
separately states the portion of the transaction that is not subject to taxation under this chapter on an invoice, bill of sale, or similar document provided to the purchaser; or
(B)
is able to identify by reasonable and verifiable standards, from the books and records the seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business, the portion of the transaction that is not subject to taxation under this chapter.
(ii)
A purchaser and a seller may correct the taxability of a transaction if:
(A)
after the transaction occurs, the purchaser and the seller discover that the portion of the transaction that is not subject to taxation under this chapter was not separately stated on an invoice, bill of sale, or similar document provided to the purchaser because of an error or ignorance of the law; and
(B)
the seller is able to identify by reasonable and verifiable standards, from the books and records the seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business, the portion of the transaction that is not subject to taxation under this chapter.
(iii)
For purposes of Subsections
(2)(g)(i)
and
(ii)
, books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.
(h)
(i)
If the sales price of a transaction is attributable to two or more items of tangible personal property, products, or services that are subject to taxation under this chapter at different rates, the entire purchase is subject to taxation under this chapter at the higher tax rate unless the seller, at the time of the transaction:
(A)
separately states the items subject to taxation under this chapter at each of the different rates on an invoice, bill of sale, or similar document provided to the purchaser; or
(B)
is able to identify by reasonable and verifiable standards the tangible personal property, product, or service that is subject to taxation under this chapter at the lower tax rate from the books and records the seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business.
(ii)
For purposes of Subsection
(2)(h)(i)
, books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.
(i)
Subject to Subsections
(2)(j)
and
(k)
, a tax rate repeal or tax rate change for a tax rate imposed under the following shall take effect on the first day of a calendar quarter:
(i)
Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
;
(ii)
Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(iii)
Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; or
(iv)
Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(j)
(i)
A tax rate increase takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the tax rate increase if the billing period for the transaction begins before the effective date of a tax rate increase imposed under:
(A)
Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
;
(B)
Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(C)
Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; or
(D)
Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(ii)
The repeal of a tax or a tax rate decrease applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is rendered on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax or the tax rate decrease imposed under:
(A)
Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
;
(B)
Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(C)
Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; or
(D)
Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(k)
(i)
For a tax rate described in Subsection
(2)(k)(ii)
, if a tax due on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, a tax rate repeal or change in a tax rate takes effect:
(A)
on the first day of a calendar quarter; and
(B)
beginning 60 days after the effective date of the tax rate repeal or tax rate change.
(ii)
Subsection
(2)(k)(i)
applies to the tax rates described in the following:
(A)
Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
;
(B)
Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(C)
Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; or
(D)
Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(iii)
In accordance with Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;
(l)
(i)
For a location described in Subsection
(2)(l)(ii)
, the commission shall determine the taxable status of a sale of gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel based on the predominant use of the gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel at the location.
(ii)
Subsection
(2)(l)(i)
applies to a location where gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel is furnished through a single meter for two or more of the following uses:
(A)
a commercial use;
(B)
an industrial use; or
(C)
a residential use.
(3)
(a)
The following state taxes shall be deposited into the General Fund:
(i)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
;
(ii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(iii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(iv)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(b)
The following local taxes shall be distributed to a county, city, or town as provided in this chapter:
(i)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(ii)
;
(ii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(ii)
;
(iii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(ii)
; and
(iv)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(B)
.
(c)
The state tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(d)
shall be deposited into the General Fund.
(4)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, the lesser of the following amounts shall be expended as provided in Subsections
(4)(b)
through
(g)
:
(i)
for taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
, the amount of tax revenue generated:
(A)
by a 1/16% tax rate on the transactions described in Subsection
(1)
; and
(B)
for the fiscal year; or
(ii)
$17,500,000.
(b)
(i)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 14% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Wildlife Resources to:
(A)
implement the measures described in Subsections
23A-3-214(3)(a)
through (d) to protect sensitive plant and animal species; or
(B)
award grants, up to the amount authorized by the Legislature in an appropriations act, to political subdivisions of the state to implement the measures described in Subsections
23A-3-214(3)(a)
through
(d)
to protect sensitive plant and animal species.
(ii)
Money transferred to the Division of Wildlife Resources under Subsection
(4)(b)(i)
may not be used to assist the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or any other person to list or attempt to have listed a species as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, 16 U.S.C. Sec. 1531 et seq.
(iii)
At the end of each fiscal year:
(A)
50% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
;
(B)
25% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Utah Wastewater Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
; and
(C)
25% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Drinking Water Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
.
(c)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 3% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Conservation created in Section
4-46-401
to implement water related programs.
(d)
(i)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 1% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Water Rights to cover the costs incurred in hiring legal and technical staff for the adjudication of water rights.
(ii)
At the end of each fiscal year:
(A)
50% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
;
(B)
25% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Utah Wastewater Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
; and
(C)
25% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue shall lapse to the Drinking Water Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
.
(e)
(i)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 41% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be deposited into the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
for use by the Division of Water Resources.
(ii)
In addition to the uses allowed of the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund under Section
73-10-24
, the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund may also be used to:
(A)
conduct hydrologic and geotechnical investigations by the Division of Water Resources in a cooperative effort with other state, federal, or local entities, for the purpose of quantifying surface and ground water resources and describing the hydrologic systems of an area in sufficient detail so as to enable local and state resource managers to plan for and accommodate growth in water use without jeopardizing the resource;
(B)
fund state required dam safety improvements; and
(C)
protect the state's interest in interstate water compact allocations, including the hiring of technical and legal staff.
(f)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 20.5% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be deposited into the Utah Wastewater Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
for use by the Water Quality Board to fund wastewater projects.
(g)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 20.5% of the amount described in Subsection
(4)(a)
shall be deposited into the Drinking Water Loan Program Subaccount created in Section
73-10c-5
for use by the Division of Drinking Water to:
(i)
provide for the installation and repair of collection, treatment, storage, and distribution facilities for any public water system, as defined in Section
19-4-102
;
(ii)
develop underground sources of water, including springs and wells; and
(iii)
develop surface water sources.
(5)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2006, the difference between the following amounts shall be expended as provided in this Subsection
(5)
, if that difference is greater than $1:
(i)
for taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
, the amount of tax revenue generated for the fiscal year by a 1/16% tax rate on the transactions described in Subsection
(1)
; and
(ii)
$17,500,000.
(b)
(i)
The first $500,000 of the difference described in Subsection
(5)(a)
shall be:
(A)
transferred each fiscal year to the Department of Natural Resources as designated sales and use tax revenue; and
(B)
expended by the Department of Natural Resources for watershed rehabilitation or restoration.
(ii)
At the end of each fiscal year, 100% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue described in Subsection
(5)(b)(i)
shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
.
(c)
(i)
After making the transfer required by Subsection
(5)(b)(i)
, $150,000 of the remaining difference described in Subsection
(5)(a)
shall be:
(A)
transferred each fiscal year to the Division of Water Resources as designated sales and use tax revenue; and
(B)
expended by the Division of Water Resources for cloud-seeding projects authorized by Title
73, Chapter 15
, Modification of Weather.
(ii)
At the end of each fiscal year, 100% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue described in Subsection
(5)(c)(i)
shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
.
(d)
After making the transfers required by Subsections
(5)(b)
and
(c)
, 85% of the remaining difference described in Subsection
(5)(a)
shall be deposited into the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section
73-10-24
for use by the Division of Water Resources for:
(i)
preconstruction costs:
(A)
as defined in Subsection
73-26-103(6)
for projects authorized by Title 73, Chapter 26, Bear River Development Act; and
(B)
as defined in Subsection
73-28-103(8)
for the Lake Powell Pipeline project authorized by Title 73, Chapter 28, Lake Powell Pipeline Development Act;
(ii)
the cost of employing a civil engineer to oversee any project authorized by Title 73, Chapter 26, Bear River Development Act;
(iii)
the cost of employing a civil engineer to oversee the Lake Powell Pipeline project authorized by Title 73, Chapter 28, Lake Powell Pipeline Development Act; and
(iv)
other uses authorized under Sections
73-10-24
,
73-10-25.1
, and
73-10-30
, and Subsection
(4)(e)(ii)
after funding the uses specified in Subsections
(5)(d)(i)
through
(iii)
.
(e)
After making the transfers required by Subsections
(5)(b)
and
(c)
, 15% of the remaining difference described in Subsection
(5)(a)
shall be deposited each year into the Water Rights Restricted Account created by Section
73-2-1.6
.
(6)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
and for taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
, each fiscal year, the commission shall deposit into the Water Infrastructure Restricted Account created in Section
73-10g-103
the amount of revenue generated by a 1/16% tax rate on the transactions described in Subsection
(1)
for the fiscal year.
(7)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
and subject to Subsections
(7)(b)
, (c), and (d), for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the commission shall deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 created by Section
72-2-124
a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
equal to 24% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:
(i)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate;
(ii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(iii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(iv)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(b)
(i)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2024, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit under Subsection
(7)(a)
into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 by an amount equal to .44% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:
(A)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate;
(B)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(C)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(D)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(ii)
The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection
(7)(b)(i)
into the Cottonwood Canyons Transportation Investment Fund created in Section
72-2-124
.
(c)
(i)
Subject to Subsection
(7)(c)(ii)
, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under Subsections
(7)(a)
and
(7)(b)
by an amount that is equal to 5% of:
(A)
the amount of revenue generated in the current fiscal year by the portion of taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
that equals 20.68% of the revenue collected from taxes described in Subsections
(7)(a)(i)
through
(iv)
;
(B)
the amount of revenue generated in the current fiscal year by registration fees designated under Section
41-1a-1201
to be deposited into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005; and
(C)
revenue transferred by the Division of Finance to the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 in accordance with Section
72-2-106
in the current fiscal year.
(ii)
The amount described in Subsection
(7)(c)(i)
may not exceed $45,000,000 in a given fiscal year.
(iii)
The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection
(7)(c)(i)
into the Active Transportation Investment Fund created in Subsection
72-2-124(11)
.
(d)
(i)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2024, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under this Subsection
(7)
by an amount that is equal to 1% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:
(A)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate;
(B)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(C)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(D)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(ii)
The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection
(7)(d)(i)
into the Commuter Rail Subaccount created in Section
72-2-124
.
(8)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, in addition to the amounts deposited under Subsection
(7)
, and subject to Subsection
(8)(b)
, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2018, the commission shall annually deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 created by Section
72-2-124
a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
in an amount equal to 3.68% of the revenue collected from the following taxes:
(i)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate;
(ii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(iii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(iv)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(b)
For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2019, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under Subsection
(8)(a)
by an amount that is equal to 35% of the amount of revenue generated in the current fiscal year by the portion of the tax imposed on motor and special fuel that is sold, used, or received for sale or use in this state that exceeds 29.4 cents per gallon.
(c)
The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection
(8)(b)
into the Transit Transportation Investment Fund created in Section
72-2-124
.
(9)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2009-10, $533,750 shall be deposited into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund created by Section
35A-8-1009
and expended as provided in Section
35A-8-1009
.
(10)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, beginning the second fiscal year after the fiscal year during which the commission receives notice under Section
63N-2-510
that construction on a qualified hotel, as defined in Section
63N-2-502
, has begun, the commission shall, for two consecutive fiscal years, annually deposit $1,900,000 of the revenue generated by the taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
into the Hotel Impact Mitigation Fund, created in Section
63N-2-512
.
(11)
(a)
The rate specified in this subsection is 0.15%.
(b)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, the commission shall, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2019, annually transfer the amount of revenue collected from the rate described in Subsection
(11)(a)
on the transactions that are subject to the sales and use tax under Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
into the Medicaid ACA Fund created in Section
26B-1-315
.
(12)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2020-21, the commission shall deposit $200,000 into the General Fund as a dedicated credit solely for use of the Search and Rescue Financial Assistance Program created in, and expended in accordance with, Title 53, Chapter 2a, Part 11, Search and Rescue Act.
(13)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, and except as provided in Subsections
(17)
and
(18)
, and as described in Section
63N-3-610
, beginning the first day of a calendar quarter one year after the sales and use tax boundary for a housing and transit reinvestment zone is established under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 15% of the sales and use tax increment from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in Section
63N-3-602
, into the Transit Transportation Investment Fund created in Section
72-2-124
.
(b)
Beginning no sooner than January 1, 2026, notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, and except as provided in Subsections
(17)
and
(18)
, and as described in Section
63N-3-610.1
, beginning the first day of a calendar quarter after the year set in the proposal and after the sales and use tax boundary for a convention center reinvestment zone is established in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 50% of the sales and use tax increment as defined in Section
63N-3-602
from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in Section
63N-3-602
, to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section
17D-4-202.1
and specified in the convention center reinvestment zone proposal submitted pursuant to Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act.
(14)
(a)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2025, the commission shall, in accordance with Subsection
(14)(b)
, transfer a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection
(3)(a)
equal to 1% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:
(i)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate;
(ii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(b)(i)
;
(iii)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(c)(i)
; and
(iv)
the tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(f)(i)(A)(I)
.
(b)
The commission shall transfer the portion of the taxes described in Subsection
(14)(a)
as follows:
(i)
into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account created in Section
51-9-902
, an amount equal to the amount that was deposited into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account in fiscal year 2025; and
(ii)
for any amount exceeding the amount described in Subsection
(14)(b)(i)
, 50% into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account and 50% to the Utah Fairpark Area Investment and Restoration District created in Section
11-70-201
.
(15)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, and except as provided in Subsections
(17)
and
(18)
, beginning October 1, 2024 the commission shall transfer to the Utah Fairpark Area Investment and Restoration District, created in Section
11-70-201
, the revenue from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within the district sales tax area, as defined in Section
11-70-101
.
(16)
(a)
As used in this Subsection
(16)
:
(i)
&quot;Additional land&quot; means point of the mountain state land described in Subsection
11-59-102(6)(b)
that the point of the mountain authority acquires after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map under Subsection
(16)(c)
.
(ii)
&quot;Point of the mountain authority&quot; means the Point of the Mountain State Land Authority, created in Section
11-59-201
.
(iii)
&quot;Point of the mountain state land&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
11-59-102
.
(b)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(3)(a)
, and except as provided in Subsections
(17)
and
(18)
, the commission shall distribute to the point of the mountain authority 50% of the revenue from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring on the point of the mountain state land.
(c)
The distribution under Subsection
(16)(b)
shall begin the next calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map that:
(i)
accurately describes the point of the mountain state land; and
(ii)
the point of the mountain authority certifies as accurate.
(d)
A distribution under Subsection
(16)(b)
with respect to additional land shall begin the next calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map of point of the mountain state land that:
(i)
accurately describes the point of the mountain state land, including the additional land; and
(ii)
the point of the mountain authority certifies as accurate.
(e)
(i)
Upon the payment in full of bonds secured by the sales and use tax revenue distributed to the point of the mountain authority under Subsection
(16)(b)
, the point of the mountain authority shall immediately notify the commission in writing that the bonds are paid in full.
(ii)
The commission shall discontinue distributions of sales and use tax revenue under Subsection
(16)(b)
at the beginning of the calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the date that the commission receives the written notice under Subsection
(16)(e)(i)
.
(17)
(a)
As used in Subsections
(17)
and
(18)
:
(i)
&quot;Applicable percentage&quot; means, for a convention center reinvestment zone created in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, an amount equal to 50% of the sales and use tax increment, as that term is defined in Section
63N-3-602
, from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection
(2)(a)(i)(A)
at a 4.7% rate for sales occurring within the qualified development zone described in Subsection
(17)(a)(ii)
.
(ii)
&quot;Qualified development zone&quot; means the sales and use tax boundary of a convention center reinvestment zone created in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act.
(iii)
&quot;Qualifying construction materials&quot; means construction materials that are:
(A)
delivered to a delivery outlet within a qualified development zone; and
(B)
intended to be permanently attached to real property within the qualified development zone.
(b)
For a sale of qualifying construction materials, the commission shall distribute the product calculated in Subsection
(17)(c)
to a qualified development zone if the seller of the construction materials:
(i)
establishes a delivery outlet with the commission within the qualified development zone;
(ii)
reports the sales of the construction materials to the delivery outlet described in Subsection
(17)(b)(i)
; and
(iii)
does not report the sales of the construction materials on a simplified electronic return.
(c)
For the purposes of Subsection
(17)(b)
, the product is equal to:
(i)
the sales price or purchase price of the qualifying construction materials; and
(ii)
the applicable percentage.
(18)
(a)
As used in this Subsection
(18)
, &quot;Schedule J sale&quot; means a sale reported on State Tax Commission Form TC-62M, Schedule J, or a substantially similar form as designated by the commission.
(b)
Revenue generated from the applicable percentage by a Schedule J sale within a qualified development zone shall be distributed into the General Fund.
Amended by Chapter
452
, 2025 General Session
Amended by Chapter
498
, 2025 General Session</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A tax is imposed on the purchaser as provided in this part on the purchase price or sales price for amounts paid or charged for the following transactions:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>retail sales of tangible personal property made within the state;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid for:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>telecommunications service, other than mobile telecommunications service, that originates and terminates within the boundaries of this state;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>mobile telecommunications service that originates and terminates within the boundaries of one state only to the extent permitted by the Mobile Telecommunications Sourcing Act, 4 U.S.C. Sec. 116 et seq.; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>an ancillary service associated with a:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>sales of the following for commercial use:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>gas;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>electricity;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>heat;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>coal;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>fuel oil; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_vi">
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>other fuels;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>sales of the following for residential use:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>gas;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>electricity;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>heat;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>coal;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>fuel oil; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_vi">
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>other fuels;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>sales of prepared food;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>except as provided in Section , amounts paid or charged as admission or user fees for theaters, movies, operas, museums, planetariums, shows of any type or nature, exhibitions, concerts, carnivals, amusement parks, amusement rides, circuses, menageries, fairs, races, contests, sporting events, dances, boxing matches, wrestling matches, closed circuit television broadcasts, billiard parlors, pool parlors, bowling lanes, golf, miniature golf, golf driving ranges, batting cages, skating rinks, ski lifts, ski runs, ski trails, snowmobile trails, tennis courts, swimming pools, water slides, river runs, jeep tours, boat tours, scenic cruises, horseback rides, sports activities, or any other amusement, entertainment, recreation, exhibition, cultural, or athletic activity;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for services for repairs or renovations of tangible personal property, unless Section provides for an exemption from sales and use tax for:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tangible personal property; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>parts used in the repairs or renovations of the tangible personal property described in Subsection , regardless of whether:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>except as provided in Subsection , amounts paid or charged for assisted cleaning or washing of tangible personal property;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for short-term rentals of tourist home, hotel, motel, or trailer court accommodations and services;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for laundry or dry cleaning services;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for leases or rentals of tangible personal property if within this state the tangible personal property is:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>stored;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>used; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>otherwise consumed;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for tangible personal property if within this state the tangible personal property is:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_l__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>stored;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_l__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>used; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_l__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>consumed;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <content>
                <p>amounts paid or charged for a sale:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_m__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_m__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>regardless of whether the sale provides:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_1__para_n">
              <num>(n)</num>
              <content>
                <p>sales of leased tangible personal property from the lessor to the lessee made in the state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsections through , a state tax and a local tax are imposed on a transaction described in Subsection equal to the sum of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a state tax imposed on the transaction at a tax rate equal to the sum of:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the transaction under this chapter other than this part.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection or and subject to Subsection , a state tax and a local tax are imposed on a transaction described in Subsection equal to the sum of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a state tax imposed on the transaction at a tax rate of 2%; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the transaction under this chapter other than this part.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection or , a state tax and a local tax are imposed on amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients equal to the sum of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a state tax imposed on the amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients at a tax rate of 1.75%; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>a local tax equal to the sum of the tax rates a county, city, or town imposes on the amounts paid or charged for food and food ingredients under this chapter other than this part.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection or (g), a state tax is imposed on amounts paid or charged for fuel to a common carrier that is a railroad for use in a locomotive engine at a rate of 4.85%.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A tax imposed under Subsection or applies to car sharing.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If all shared vehicles shared through a car-sharing program are certified as described in Subsection for a tax period, the car-sharing program has no obligation to collect and remit the tax under Subsection for that tax period.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A car-sharing program is not required to list or otherwise identify an individual-owned shared vehicle on a return or an attachment to a return.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_vi">
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A car-sharing program shall:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a bundled transaction that is attributable to food and food ingredients and tangible personal property other than food and food ingredients, a state tax and a local tax is imposed on the entire bundled transaction equal to the sum of:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If an optional computer software maintenance contract is a bundled transaction that consists of taxable and nontaxable products that are not separately itemized on an invoice or similar billing document, the purchase of the optional computer software maintenance contract is 40% taxable under this chapter and 60% nontaxable under this chapter.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsection , for a bundled transaction other than a bundled transaction described in Subsection or :</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of Subsection , books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as otherwise provided in this chapter and subject to Subsections and , if a transaction consists of the sale, lease, or rental of tangible personal property, a product, or a service that is subject to taxation under this chapter, and the sale, lease, or rental of tangible personal property, other property, a product, or a service that is not subject to taxation under this chapter, the entire transaction is subject to taxation under this chapter unless the seller, at the time of the transaction:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A purchaser and a seller may correct the taxability of a transaction if:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_g__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of Subsections and , books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_h__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the sales price of a transaction is attributable to two or more items of tangible personal property, products, or services that are subject to taxation under this chapter at different rates, the entire purchase is subject to taxation under this chapter at the higher tax rate unless the seller, at the time of the transaction:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_h__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of Subsection , books and records that a seller keeps in the seller's regular course of business includes books and records the seller keeps in the regular course of business for nontax purposes.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsections and , a tax rate repeal or tax rate change for a tax rate imposed under the following shall take effect on the first day of a calendar quarter:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_i__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_i__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_i__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection ; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_i__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_j__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A tax rate increase takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the tax rate increase if the billing period for the transaction begins before the effective date of a tax rate increase imposed under:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_j__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The repeal of a tax or a tax rate decrease applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is rendered on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax or the tax rate decrease imposed under:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_k__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a tax rate described in Subsection , if a tax due on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, a tax rate repeal or change in a tax rate takes effect:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_k__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection applies to the tax rates described in the following:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_k__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In accordance with Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_l__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a location described in Subsection , the commission shall determine the taxable status of a sale of gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel based on the predominant use of the gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel at the location.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_2__para_l__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subsection applies to a location where gas, electricity, heat, coal, fuel oil, or other fuel is furnished through a single meter for two or more of the following uses:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The following state taxes shall be deposited into the General Fund:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The following local taxes shall be distributed to a county, city, or town as provided in this chapter:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_3__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The state tax imposed by Subsection shall be deposited into the General Fund.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, the lesser of the following amounts shall be expended as provided in Subsections through :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>for taxes listed under Subsection , the amount of tax revenue generated:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>$17,500,000.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 14% of the amount described in Subsection shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Wildlife Resources to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Money transferred to the Division of Wildlife Resources under Subsection may not be used to assist the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or any other person to list or attempt to have listed a species as threatened or endangered under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, 16 U.S.C. Sec. 1531 et seq.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the end of each fiscal year:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 3% of the amount described in Subsection shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Conservation created in Section to implement water related programs.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 1% of the amount described in Subsection shall be transferred each year as designated sales and use tax revenue to the Division of Water Rights to cover the costs incurred in hiring legal and technical staff for the adjudication of water rights.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the end of each fiscal year:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 41% of the amount described in Subsection shall be deposited into the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section for use by the Division of Water Resources.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In addition to the uses allowed of the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund under Section , the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund may also be used to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 20.5% of the amount described in Subsection shall be deposited into the Utah Wastewater Loan Program Subaccount created in Section for use by the Water Quality Board to fund wastewater projects.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2003, 20.5% of the amount described in Subsection shall be deposited into the Drinking Water Loan Program Subaccount created in Section for use by the Division of Drinking Water to:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>provide for the installation and repair of collection, treatment, storage, and distribution facilities for any public water system, as defined in Section ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>develop underground sources of water, including springs and wells; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_4__para_g__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>develop surface water sources.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2006, the difference between the following amounts shall be expended as provided in this Subsection , if that difference is greater than $1:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>for taxes listed under Subsection , the amount of tax revenue generated for the fiscal year by a 1/16% tax rate on the transactions described in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>$17,500,000.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The first $500,000 of the difference described in Subsection shall be:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the end of each fiscal year, 100% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue described in Subsection shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>After making the transfer required by Subsection , $150,000 of the remaining difference described in Subsection shall be:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At the end of each fiscal year, 100% of any unexpended designated sales and use tax revenue described in Subsection shall lapse to the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>After making the transfers required by Subsections and , 85% of the remaining difference described in Subsection shall be deposited into the Water Resources Conservation and Development Fund created in Section for use by the Division of Water Resources for:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>preconstruction costs:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the cost of employing a civil engineer to oversee any project authorized by Title 73, Chapter 26, Bear River Development Act;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_d__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the cost of employing a civil engineer to oversee the Lake Powell Pipeline project authorized by Title 73, Chapter 28, Lake Powell Pipeline Development Act; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_d__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>other uses authorized under Sections , , and , and Subsection after funding the uses specified in Subsections through .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_5__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>After making the transfers required by Subsections and , 15% of the remaining difference described in Subsection shall be deposited each year into the Water Rights Restricted Account created by Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Subsection and for taxes listed under Subsection , each fiscal year, the commission shall deposit into the Water Infrastructure Restricted Account created in Section the amount of revenue generated by a 1/16% tax rate on the transactions described in Subsection for the fiscal year.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection and subject to Subsections , (c), and (d), for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the commission shall deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 created by Section a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection equal to 24% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2024, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit under Subsection into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 by an amount equal to .44% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection into the Cottonwood Canyons Transportation Investment Fund created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsection , for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under Subsections and by an amount that is equal to 5% of:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The amount described in Subsection may not exceed $45,000,000 in a given fiscal year.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection into the Active Transportation Investment Fund created in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2024, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under this Subsection by an amount that is equal to 1% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection into the Commuter Rail Subaccount created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , in addition to the amounts deposited under Subsection , and subject to Subsection , for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2018, the commission shall annually deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 created by Section a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection in an amount equal to 3.68% of the revenue collected from the following taxes:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2019, the commission shall annually reduce the deposit into the Transportation Investment Fund of 2005 under Subsection by an amount that is equal to 35% of the amount of revenue generated in the current fiscal year by the portion of the tax imposed on motor and special fuel that is sold, used, or received for sale or use in this state that exceeds 29.4 cents per gallon.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_8__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall annually deposit the amount described in Subsection into the Transit Transportation Investment Fund created in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2009-10, $533,750 shall be deposited into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund created by Section and expended as provided in Section .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , beginning the second fiscal year after the fiscal year during which the commission receives notice under Section that construction on a qualified hotel, as defined in Section , has begun, the commission shall, for two consecutive fiscal years, annually deposit $1,900,000 of the revenue generated by the taxes listed under Subsection into the Hotel Impact Mitigation Fund, created in Section .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_11__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The rate specified in this subsection is 0.15%.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_11__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , the commission shall, for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2019, annually transfer the amount of revenue collected from the rate described in Subsection on the transactions that are subject to the sales and use tax under Subsection into the Medicaid ACA Fund created in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_12">
            <num>(12)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , for each fiscal year beginning with fiscal year 2020-21, the commission shall deposit $200,000 into the General Fund as a dedicated credit solely for use of the Search and Rescue Financial Assistance Program created in, and expended in accordance with, Title 53, Chapter 2a, Part 11, Search and Rescue Act.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_13">
            <num>(13)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_13__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , and except as provided in Subsections and , and as described in Section , beginning the first day of a calendar quarter one year after the sales and use tax boundary for a housing and transit reinvestment zone is established under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 15% of the sales and use tax increment from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in Section , into the Transit Transportation Investment Fund created in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_13__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Beginning no sooner than January 1, 2026, notwithstanding Subsection , and except as provided in Subsections and , and as described in Section , beginning the first day of a calendar quarter after the year set in the proposal and after the sales and use tax boundary for a convention center reinvestment zone is established in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 50% of the sales and use tax increment as defined in Section from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in Section , to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section and specified in the convention center reinvestment zone proposal submitted pursuant to Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_14">
            <num>(14)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , for a fiscal year beginning on or after July 1, 2025, the commission shall, in accordance with Subsection , transfer a portion of the taxes listed under Subsection equal to 1% of the revenue collected from the following sales and use taxes:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_a__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the tax imposed by Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall transfer the portion of the taxes described in Subsection as follows:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account created in Section , an amount equal to the amount that was deposited into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account in fiscal year 2025; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_14__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>for any amount exceeding the amount described in Subsection , 50% into the Outdoor Adventure Infrastructure Restricted Account and 50% to the Utah Fairpark Area Investment and Restoration District created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_15">
            <num>(15)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , and except as provided in Subsections and , beginning October 1, 2024 the commission shall transfer to the Utah Fairpark Area Investment and Restoration District, created in Section , the revenue from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring within the district sales tax area, as defined in Section .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_16">
            <num>(16)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>As used in this Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Additional land&quot; means point of the mountain state land described in Subsection that the point of the mountain authority acquires after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map under Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Point of the mountain authority&quot; means the Point of the Mountain State Land Authority, created in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Point of the mountain state land&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , and except as provided in Subsections and , the commission shall distribute to the point of the mountain authority 50% of the revenue from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate, on transactions occurring on the point of the mountain state land.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The distribution under Subsection shall begin the next calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map that:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>accurately describes the point of the mountain state land; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the point of the mountain authority certifies as accurate.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A distribution under Subsection with respect to additional land shall begin the next calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the point of the mountain authority provides the commission a map of point of the mountain state land that:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>accurately describes the point of the mountain state land, including the additional land; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the point of the mountain authority certifies as accurate.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Upon the payment in full of bonds secured by the sales and use tax revenue distributed to the point of the mountain authority under Subsection , the point of the mountain authority shall immediately notify the commission in writing that the bonds are paid in full.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_16__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall discontinue distributions of sales and use tax revenue under Subsection at the beginning of the calendar quarter that begins at least 90 days after the date that the commission receives the written notice under Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_17">
            <num>(17)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>As used in Subsections and :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Applicable percentage&quot; means, for a convention center reinvestment zone created in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, an amount equal to 50% of the sales and use tax increment, as that term is defined in Section , from the sales and use tax imposed by Subsection at a 4.7% rate for sales occurring within the qualified development zone described in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Qualified development zone&quot; means the sales and use tax boundary of a convention center reinvestment zone created in a capital city under Title 63N, Chapter 3, Part 6, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Qualifying construction materials&quot; means construction materials that are:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a sale of qualifying construction materials, the commission shall distribute the product calculated in Subsection to a qualified development zone if the seller of the construction materials:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>establishes a delivery outlet with the commission within the qualified development zone;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>reports the sales of the construction materials to the delivery outlet described in Subsection ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>does not report the sales of the construction materials on a simplified electronic return.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the purposes of Subsection , the product is equal to:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the sales price or purchase price of the qualifying construction materials; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_17__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the applicable percentage.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_103__subsec_18">
            <num>(18)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_18__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>As used in this Subsection , &quot;Schedule J sale&quot; means a sale reported on State Tax Commission Form TC-62M, Schedule J, or a substantially similar form as designated by the commission.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_103__subsec_18__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Revenue generated from the applicable percentage by a Schedule J sale within a qualified development zone shall be distributed into the General Fund.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
