<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-1102/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_12">
        <num>Chapter 59-12</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_12_1102">
          <num>59-12-1102</num>
          <heading>Base -- Rate -- Imposition of tax -- Distribution of revenue -- Administration -- Administrative charge -- Commission requirement to retain an amount to be deposited into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund -- Enactment or repeal of tax -- Effective date -- Notice requirements.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 11/6/2025
59-12-1102.
Base -- Rate -- Imposition of tax -- Distribution of revenue -- Administration -- Administrative charge -- Commission requirement to retain an amount to be deposited into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund -- Enactment or repeal of tax -- Effective date -- Notice requirements.
(1)
(a)
(i)
Subject to Subsections
(2)
through (7), and in addition to any other tax authorized by this chapter, a county may impose by ordinance a county option sales and use tax of .25%  upon the transactions described in Subsection
59-12-103(1)
.
(ii)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(1)(a)(i)
, a county may not impose a tax under this section on the sales and uses described in Section
59-12-104
to the extent the sales and uses are exempt from taxation under Section
59-12-104
.
(b)
For purposes of this Subsection
(1)
, the location of a transaction shall be determined in accordance with Sections
59-12-211
through
59-12-215
.
(c)
The county option sales and use tax under this section shall be imposed:
(i)
upon transactions that are located within the county, including transactions that are located within municipalities in the county; and
(ii)
except as provided in Subsection
(1)(d)
or (6), beginning on the first day of January:
(A)
of the next calendar year after adoption of the ordinance imposing the tax if the ordinance is adopted on or before May 25; or
(B)
of the second calendar year after adoption of the ordinance imposing the tax if the ordinance is adopted after May 25.
(d)
The county option sales and use tax under this section shall be imposed:
(i)
beginning January 1, 1998, if an ordinance adopting the tax imposed on or before September 4, 1997; or
(ii)
beginning January 1, 1999, if an ordinance adopting the tax is imposed during 1997 but after September 4, 1997.
(2)
(a)
Before imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection
(1)
, a county shall hold two public hearings on separate days in geographically diverse locations in the county.
(b)
(i)
At least one of the hearings required by Subsection
(2)(a)
shall have a starting time of no earlier than 6 p.m.
(ii)
The earlier of the hearings required by Subsection
(2)(a)
shall be no less than seven days after the day the first advertisement required by Subsection
(2)(c)
is published.
(c)
(i)
Before holding the public hearings required by Subsection
(2)(a)
, the county shall advertise:
(A)
its intent to adopt a county option sales and use tax;
(B)
the date, time, and location of each public hearing; and
(C)
a statement that the purpose of each public hearing is to obtain public comments regarding the proposed tax.
(ii)
The advertisement shall be published:
(A)
in a newspaper of general circulation in the county once each week for the two weeks preceding the earlier of the two public hearings; and
(B)
for the county, as a class A notice under Section
63G-30-102
, for two weeks before the day on which the first of the two public hearings is held.
(iii)
The advertisement described in Subsection
(2)(c)(ii)(A)
shall be no less than 1/8 page in size, and the type used shall be no smaller than 18 point and surrounded by a 1/4-inch border.
(iv)
The advertisement described in Subsection
(2)(c)(ii)(A)
may not be placed in that portion of the newspaper where legal notices and classified advertisements appear.
(v)
In accordance with Subsection
(2)(c)(ii)(A)
, whenever possible:
(A)
the advertisement shall appear in a newspaper that is published at least five days a week, unless the only newspaper in the county is published less than five days a week; and
(B)
the newspaper selected shall be one of general interest and readership in the community, and not one of limited subject matter.
(d)
The adoption of an ordinance imposing a county option sales and use tax is subject to a local referendum election and shall be conducted as provided in
Title 20A, Chapter 7, Part 6, Local Referenda - Procedures
.
(3)
Beginning no sooner than January 1, 2026, and subject to Section
59-12-205
, before application of Subsections
(4)
through
(7)
, and as described in Section
63N-3-610.1
, beginning the first day of a calendar quarter after the year set in the proposal and after the sales and use tax boundary for a convention center reinvestment zone is established under Title
63N, Chapter 3, Part 6
, Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 100% of the sales and use tax increment as defined in Section
63N-3-602
, from the sales and use tax imposed under this part on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in  Section
63N-3-602
, to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section
17D-4-202.1
.
(4)
(a)
Subject to Subsection
(6)
, if the aggregate population of the counties imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection
(1)
is less than 75% of the state population, the tax levied under Subsection
(1)
shall be distributed to the county in which the tax was collected.
(b)
Subject to Subsection
(6)
, if the aggregate population of the counties imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection
(1)
is greater than or equal to 75% of the state population:
(i)
50% of the tax collected under Subsection
(1)
in each county shall be distributed to the county in which the tax was collected; and
(ii)
except as provided in Subsection
(4)(c)
, 50% of the tax collected under Subsection
(1)
in each county shall be distributed proportionately among all counties imposing the tax, based on the total population of each county.
(c)
Except as provided in Subsection
(6)
, the amount to be distributed annually to a county under Subsection
(4)(b)(ii)
, when combined with the amount distributed to the county under Subsection
(4)(b)(i)
, does not equal at least $75,000, then:
(i)
the amount to be distributed annually to that county under Subsection
(4)(b)(ii)
shall be increased so that, when combined with the amount distributed to the county under Subsection
(4)(b)(i)
, the amount distributed annually to the county is $75,000; and
(ii)
the amount to be distributed annually to all other counties under Subsection
(4)(b)(ii)
shall be reduced proportionately to offset the additional amount distributed under Subsection
(4)(c)(i)
.
(d)
The commission shall establish rules to implement the distribution of the tax under Subsections
(4)(a)
,
(b)
, and
(c)
.
(e)
Population for each county for purposes of this Subsection (4) shall be based on, to the extent not otherwise required by federal law:
(i)
the estimate of the Utah Population Committee created in Section
63C-20-103
; or
(ii)
if the Utah Population Committee estimate is not available, the most recent census or census estimate of the United States Bureau of the Census.
(5)
(a)
Except as provided in Subsection
(5)(b)
or
(c)
, a tax authorized under this part shall be administered, collected, enforced, and interpreted in accordance with:
(i)
the same procedures used to administer, collect, enforce, and interpret the tax under:
(A)
Part 1, Tax Collection
; or
(B)
Part 2, Local Sales and Use Tax Act
; and
(ii)
Chapter 1, General Taxation Policies
.
(b)
A tax under this part is not subject to Subsections
59-12-205(2)
and (4) through (6).
(c)
(i)
Subject to Subsection
(5)(c)(ii)
, the commission shall retain and deposit an administrative charge in accordance with Section
59-1-306
from the revenue the commission collects from a tax under this part.
(ii)
Notwithstanding Section
59-1-306
, the administrative charge described in Subsection
(5)(c)(i)
shall be calculated by taking a percentage described in Section
59-1-306
of the distribution amounts resulting after:
(A)
the applicable distribution calculations under Subsection
(4)
have been made; and
(B)
the commission retains the amount required by Subsection
(6)
.
(6)
(a)
Beginning on July 1, 2009, the commission shall calculate and retain a portion of the sales and use tax collected under this part as provided in this Subsection
(6)
.
(b)
For a county that imposes a tax under this part, the commission shall calculate a percentage each month by dividing the sales and use tax collected under this part for that month within the boundaries of that county by the total sales and use tax collected under this part for that month within the boundaries of all of the counties that impose a tax under this part.
(c)
For a county that imposes a tax under this part, the commission shall retain each month an amount equal to the product of:
(i)
the percentage the commission determines for the month under Subsection
(6)(b)
for the county; and
(ii)
$6,354.
(d)
The commission shall deposit an amount the commission retains in accordance with this Subsection
(6)
into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund created by Section
35A-8-1009
.
(e)
An amount the commission deposits into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund shall be expended as provided in Section
35A-8-1009
.
(7)
(a)
For purposes of this Subsection
(7)
:
(i)
&quot;Annexation&quot; means an annexation to a county under Title
17, Chapter 61, Part 2
, Consolidation of Counties, or Part 3, County Annexation.
(ii)
&quot;Annexing area&quot; means an area that is annexed into a county.
(b)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(7)(c)
or
(d)
, if, on or after July 1, 2004, a county enacts or repeals a tax under this part:
(A)
(I)
the enactment shall take effect as provided in Subsection
(1)(c)
; or
(II)
the repeal shall take effect on the first day of a calendar quarter; and
(B)
after a 90-day period beginning on the date the commission receives notice meeting the requirements of Subsection
(7)(b)(ii)
from the county.
(ii)
The notice described in Subsection
(7)(b)(i)(B)
shall state:
(A)
that the county will enact or repeal a tax under this part;
(B)
the statutory authority for the tax described in Subsection
(7)(b)(ii)(A)
;
(C)
the effective date of the tax described in Subsection
(7)(b)(ii)(A)
; and
(D)
if the county enacts the tax described in Subsection
(7)(b)(ii)(A)
, the rate of the tax.
(c)
(i)
If the billing period for a transaction begins before the effective date of the enactment of the tax under Subsection
(1)
, the enactment of the tax takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the enactment of the tax.
(ii)
The repeal of a tax applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is produced on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax imposed under Subsection
(1)
.
(d)
(i)
If a tax due under this chapter on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, an enactment or repeal of a tax described in Subsection
(7)(b)(i)
takes effect:
(A)
on the first day of a calendar quarter; and
(B)
beginning 60 days after the effective date of the enactment or repeal under Subsection
(7)(b)(i)
.
(ii)
In accordance with
Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act
, the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;
(e)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(7)(f)
or
(g)
, if, for an annexation that occurs on or after July 1, 2004, the annexation will result in the enactment or repeal of a tax under this part for an annexing area, the enactment or repeal shall take effect:
(A)
on the first day of a calendar quarter; and
(B)
after a 90-day period beginning on the date the commission receives notice meeting the requirements of Subsection
(7)(e)(i)
from the county that annexes the annexing area.
(ii)
The notice described in Subsection
(7)(e)(i)(B)
shall state:
(A)
that the annexation described in Subsection
(7)(b)(i)
will result in an enactment or repeal of a tax under this part for the annexing area;
(B)
the statutory authority for the tax described in Subsection
(7)(e)(ii)(A)
;
(C)
the effective date of the tax described in Subsection
(7)(e)(ii)(A)
; and
(D)
the rate of the tax described in Subsection
(7)(e)(ii)(A)
.
(f)
(i)
If the billing period for a transaction begins before the effective date of the enactment of the tax under Subsection
(1)
, the enactment of the tax takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the enactment of the tax.
(ii)
The repeal of a tax applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is produced on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax imposed under Subsection
(1)
.
(g)
(i)
If a tax due under this chapter on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, an enactment or repeal of a tax described in Subsection
(7)(e)(i)
takes effect:
(A)
on the first day of a calendar quarter; and
(B)
beginning 60 days after the effective date of the enactment or repeal under Subsection
(7)(e)(i)
.
(ii)
In accordance with
Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act
, the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;
Amended by Chapter
17
, 2025 Special Session 1</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsections through (7), and in addition to any other tax authorized by this chapter, a county may impose by ordinance a county option sales and use tax of .25%  upon the transactions described in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding Subsection , a county may not impose a tax under this section on the sales and uses described in Section to the extent the sales and uses are exempt from taxation under Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this Subsection , the location of a transaction shall be determined in accordance with Sections through .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county option sales and use tax under this section shall be imposed:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>upon transactions that are located within the county, including transactions that are located within municipalities in the county; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>except as provided in Subsection or (6), beginning on the first day of January:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county option sales and use tax under this section shall be imposed:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>beginning January 1, 1998, if an ordinance adopting the tax imposed on or before September 4, 1997; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>beginning January 1, 1999, if an ordinance adopting the tax is imposed during 1997 but after September 4, 1997.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Before imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection , a county shall hold two public hearings on separate days in geographically diverse locations in the county.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>At least one of the hearings required by Subsection shall have a starting time of no earlier than 6 p.m.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The earlier of the hearings required by Subsection shall be no less than seven days after the day the first advertisement required by Subsection is published.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Before holding the public hearings required by Subsection , the county shall advertise:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The advertisement shall be published:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The advertisement described in Subsection shall be no less than 1/8 page in size, and the type used shall be no smaller than 18 point and surrounded by a 1/4-inch border.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The advertisement described in Subsection may not be placed in that portion of the newspaper where legal notices and classified advertisements appear.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_c__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In accordance with Subsection , whenever possible:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_2__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The adoption of an ordinance imposing a county option sales and use tax is subject to a local referendum election and shall be conducted as provided in .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Beginning no sooner than January 1, 2026, and subject to Section , before application of Subsections through , and as described in Section , beginning the first day of a calendar quarter after the year set in the proposal and after the sales and use tax boundary for a convention center reinvestment zone is established under Title , Housing and Transit Reinvestment Zone Act, the commission, at least annually, shall transfer an amount equal to 100% of the sales and use tax increment as defined in Section , from the sales and use tax imposed under this part on transactions occurring within an established sales and use tax boundary, as defined in  Section , to a convention center public infrastructure district created in accordance with Section .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsection , if the aggregate population of the counties imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection is less than 75% of the state population, the tax levied under Subsection shall be distributed to the county in which the tax was collected.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsection , if the aggregate population of the counties imposing a county option sales and use tax under Subsection is greater than or equal to 75% of the state population:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>50% of the tax collected under Subsection in each county shall be distributed to the county in which the tax was collected; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>except as provided in Subsection , 50% of the tax collected under Subsection in each county shall be distributed proportionately among all counties imposing the tax, based on the total population of each county.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection , the amount to be distributed annually to a county under Subsection , when combined with the amount distributed to the county under Subsection , does not equal at least $75,000, then:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount to be distributed annually to that county under Subsection shall be increased so that, when combined with the amount distributed to the county under Subsection , the amount distributed annually to the county is $75,000; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount to be distributed annually to all other counties under Subsection shall be reduced proportionately to offset the additional amount distributed under Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall establish rules to implement the distribution of the tax under Subsections , , and .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Population for each county for purposes of this Subsection (4) shall be based on, to the extent not otherwise required by federal law:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the estimate of the Utah Population Committee created in Section ; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_4__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>if the Utah Population Committee estimate is not available, the most recent census or census estimate of the United States Bureau of the Census.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection or , a tax authorized under this part shall be administered, collected, enforced, and interpreted in accordance with:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the same procedures used to administer, collect, enforce, and interpret the tax under:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A tax under this part is not subject to Subsections and (4) through (6).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsection , the commission shall retain and deposit an administrative charge in accordance with Section from the revenue the commission collects from a tax under this part.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_5__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding Section , the administrative charge described in Subsection shall be calculated by taking a percentage described in Section of the distribution amounts resulting after:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Beginning on July 1, 2009, the commission shall calculate and retain a portion of the sales and use tax collected under this part as provided in this Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a county that imposes a tax under this part, the commission shall calculate a percentage each month by dividing the sales and use tax collected under this part for that month within the boundaries of that county by the total sales and use tax collected under this part for that month within the boundaries of all of the counties that impose a tax under this part.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For a county that imposes a tax under this part, the commission shall retain each month an amount equal to the product of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the percentage the commission determines for the month under Subsection for the county; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>$6,354.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall deposit an amount the commission retains in accordance with this Subsection into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund created by Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_6__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An amount the commission deposits into the Qualified Emergency Food Agencies Fund shall be expended as provided in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of this Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Annexation&quot; means an annexation to a county under Title , Consolidation of Counties, or Part 3, County Annexation.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>&quot;Annexing area&quot; means an area that is annexed into a county.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection or , if, on or after July 1, 2004, a county enacts or repeals a tax under this part:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The notice described in Subsection shall state:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the billing period for a transaction begins before the effective date of the enactment of the tax under Subsection , the enactment of the tax takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the enactment of the tax.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The repeal of a tax applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is produced on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax imposed under Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a tax due under this chapter on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, an enactment or repeal of a tax described in Subsection takes effect:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In accordance with , the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection or , if, for an annexation that occurs on or after July 1, 2004, the annexation will result in the enactment or repeal of a tax under this part for an annexing area, the enactment or repeal shall take effect:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The notice described in Subsection shall state:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_f__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the billing period for a transaction begins before the effective date of the enactment of the tax under Subsection , the enactment of the tax takes effect on the first day of the first billing period that begins on or after the effective date of the enactment of the tax.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_f__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The repeal of a tax applies to a billing period if the billing statement for the billing period is produced on or after the effective date of the repeal of the tax imposed under Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a tax due under this chapter on a catalogue sale is computed on the basis of sales and use tax rates published in the catalogue, an enactment or repeal of a tax described in Subsection takes effect:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_1102__subsec_7__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In accordance with , the commission may by rule define the term &quot;catalogue sale.&quot;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
