<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-306.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_2">
        <num>Chapter 59-2</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_2_306_5">
          <num>59-2-306.5</num>
          <heading>Valuation of personal property of telecommunications service provider -- Reporting information to counties.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 1/1/2024
59-2-306.5.
Valuation of personal property of telecommunications service provider -- Reporting information to counties.
(1)
As used in this section, &quot;Multicounty Appraisal Trust&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
59-2-1601
.
(2)
A telecommunications service provider shall provide to the Multicounty Appraisal Trust a signed statement setting forth all of the personal property that the telecommunications service provider owns, possesses, manages, or has under the telecommunications service provider's control in the state.
(3)
The signed statement:
(a)
may be requested by the Multicounty Appraisal Trust:
(i)
each year; and
(ii)
if requested, on or before January 31;
(b)
shall itemize each item of personal property that the telecommunications service provider owns, possesses, manages, or has under the telecommunications service provider's control:
(i)
by county and by tax area; and
(ii)
for the tax year that began on January 1; and
(c)
shall be submitted:
(i)
annually on or before March 31; and
(ii)
electronically in a form approved by the commission.
(4)
(a)
Except where an estimate is made in accordance with Subsection
59-2-307
(3)(b)(i)(C), the Multicounty Appraisal Trust shall value each item of personal property of a telecommunications service provider according to the personal property valuation guides and schedules established by the commission.
(b)
(i)
Between March 31 and May 31 of each year:
(A)
the Multicounty Appraisal Trust may communicate with a telecommunications service provider to address any inconsistency or error in the filed signed statement; and
(B)
the telecommunications service provider may file an amended signed statement with the Multicounty Appraisal Trust regarding the items agreed to by the Multicounty Appraisal Trust and the telecommunications service provider.
(ii)
The communication described in this Subsection (4)(b) is in addition to the audit authority provided by this chapter.
(c)
On or before May 31 of each year, the Multicounty Appraisal Trust shall:
(i)
forward to each county information about the total value of personal property of each telecommunications service provider within the county, by tax area, including a listing of personal property that is exempt; and
(ii)
issue a tax notice to each telecommunications service provider listing the tax due to each county, by tax area.
(d)
On or before June 30 of each year, a telecommunications service provider shall pay to the county the tax due on the tax notice.
(e)
A telecommunications service provider may appeal the valuation of personal property to the county on or before the later of:
(i)
July 30 of the year the Multicounty Appraisal Trust requests a statement described in Subsection (3)(a); or
(ii)
60 days after mailing of a tax notice.
(5)
The Multicounty Appraisal Trust shall forward to each county information about the total value of personal property of each telecommunications service provider within the county.
(6)
If a signed statement filed in accordance with this section discloses real property, the Multicounty Appraisal Trust shall send a copy of the signed statement to the county in which the property is located.
Amended by Chapter
315
, 2024 General Session</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
