<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-301.8/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_2">
        <num>Chapter 59-2</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_2_301_8">
          <num>59-2-301.8</num>
          <heading>Assessment of multi-tenant residential property.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 1/1/2021
59-2-301.8.
Assessment of multi-tenant residential property.
(1)
As used in this section:
(a)
&quot;Multi-tenant residential property&quot; means real and personal property where:
(i)
the real property:
(A)
is rented as 10 or more separate housing units;
(B)
meets the definition of residential property; and
(C)
qualifies for the residential exemption described in Section
59-2-103
; and
(ii)
the personal property is:
(A)
located within the real property; and
(B)
owned by the same person as the real property.
(b)
&quot;Multi-tenant residential property&quot; does not include a tourist home, a hotel, a motel, or a trailer court accommodation and service that is regularly rented for fewer than 30 consecutive days.
(2)
(a)
A county assessor may use an income approach to value multi-tenant residential properties within the county if the county assessor finds that the income approach is a valid indicator of fair market value for the multi-tenant residential property in the county.
(b)
A county assessor that chooses to value a multi-tenant residential property in accordance with this section shall use the same valuation method for all multi-tenant residential properties within the county.
(c)
On or before May 1, a county assessor shall notify the commission about the county's method for valuing multi-tenant residential properties if the county assessor:
(i)
(A)
chooses to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section for the current tax year; and
(B)
did not choose to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section for the previous tax year; or
(ii)
(A)
chose to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section for the previous tax year; and
(B)
is not choosing to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section for the current tax year.
(3)
(a)
If a county assessor chooses to use the income approach to value multi-tenant residential properties, the county assessor may relieve the owners of any obligation to file the signed statement requested by the county under Section
59-2-306
for the owners' personal property located within the multi-tenant residential properties.
(b)
On or before May 1:
(i)
a county assessor that chooses to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section shall notify an owner that the owner is not required to file a signed statement if:
(A)
the county requests a signed statement under Section
59-2-306
;
(B)
the county assessor relieves the owner of any obligation to file a signed statement in accordance with Subsection
(3)(a)
; and
(C)
the county assessor did not relieve the owner of the signed statement obligation for the previous tax year; or
(ii)
a county assessor that chooses not to value multi-tenant residential properties in accordance with this section shall notify an owner of the obligation to file a signed statement if:
(A)
the county requests a signed statement under Section
59-2-306
; and
(B)
the county assessor relieved the owner from filing a signed statement of personal property for the previous tax year.
(4)
For personal property for which an owner is relieved of the obligation to file a signed statement under Subsection
(3)
:
(a)
(i)
the county assessor shall assess the personal property in the same manner as real property under
Part 3, County Assessment
; and
(ii)
the county assessor or the county treasurer shall collect the tax on the personal property in the same manner as real property under
Part 13, Collection of Taxes
;
(b)
the county assessor is not required to list personal property separately in the assessment roll; and
(c)
the county auditor is not required to identify personal property separately on the statement to the commission required by Section
59-2-322
.
Enacted by Chapter
86
, 2020 General Session</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
