<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-919/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_2">
        <num>Chapter 59-2</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_2_919">
          <num>59-2-919</num>
          <heading>Notice and public hearing requirements for certain tax increases -- Exceptions -- Audit.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 11/6/2025
59-2-919.
Notice and public hearing requirements for certain tax increases -- Exceptions -- Audit.
(1)
As used in this section:
(a)
&quot;Additional ad valorem tax revenue&quot; means ad valorem property tax revenue generated by the portion of the tax rate that exceeds the taxing entity's certified tax rate.
(b)
&quot;Ad valorem tax revenue&quot; means ad valorem property tax revenue not including revenue from:
(i)
eligible new growth; or
(ii)
personal property that is:
(A)
assessed by a county assessor in accordance with Part
3, County Assessment
; and
(B)
semiconductor manufacturing equipment.
(c)
&quot;Base year&quot; means a taxing entity's fiscal year that immediately precedes the fiscal year in which the taxing entity first adopted a budget below last year's property tax budgeted revenue.
(d)
&quot;Base year budgeted revenue&quot; means the property tax budgeted revenue, excluding eligible new growth, for the base year.
(e)
&quot;Calendar year taxing entity&quot; means a taxing entity that operates under a fiscal year that begins on January 1 and ends on December 31.
(f)
&quot;County executive calendar year taxing entity&quot; means a calendar year taxing entity that operates under the county executive-council form of government described in Section
17-62-203
.
(g)
&quot;Current calendar year&quot; means the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year for which a calendar year taxing entity seeks to levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate.
(h)
&quot;Eligible new growth&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
59-2-924
.
(i)
&quot;Fiscal year taxing entity&quot; means a taxing entity that operates under a fiscal year that begins on July 1 and ends on June 30.
(j)
&quot;Meeting&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
52-4-103
.
(k)
&quot;Last year's property tax budgeted revenue&quot; does not include:
(i)
revenue received by a taxing entity from a debt service levy voted on by the public;
(ii)
revenue generated by the combined basic rate as defined in Section
53F-2-301
; or
(iii)
revenue generated by the charter school levy described in Section
53F-2-703
.
(l)
&quot;Truth-in-taxation exemption period&quot; means a six-year period that begins with the base year.
(2)
Except as provided in Subsection
(11)
, a taxing entity may not levy a tax rate that exceeds the taxing entity's certified tax rate unless the taxing entity meets:
(a)
the requirements of this section that apply to the taxing entity; and
(b)
all other requirements as may be required by law.
(3)
(a)
Subject to Subsection
(3)(b)
and except as provided in Subsection
(5)
, a calendar year taxing entity may levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate if the calendar year taxing entity:
(i)
14 or more days before the date of the regular general election or municipal general election held in the current calendar year, states at a public meeting:
(A)
that the calendar year taxing entity intends to levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate;
(B)
the dollar amount of and purpose for additional ad valorem tax revenue that would be generated by the proposed increase in the certified tax rate; and
(C)
the approximate percentage increase in ad valorem tax revenue for the taxing entity based on the proposed increase described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)(B)
;
(ii)
provides notice for the public meeting described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
in accordance with Title
52, Chapter 4
, Open and Public Meetings Act, including providing a separate item on the meeting agenda that notifies the public that the calendar year taxing entity intends to make the statement described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
;
(iii)
meets the advertisement requirements of Subsections
(6)
and
(7)
before the calendar year taxing entity conducts the public hearing required by Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
;
(iv)
provides notice by mail:
(A)
seven or more days before the regular general election or municipal general election held in the current calendar year; and
(B)
as provided in Subsection
(3)(c)
; and
(v)
conducts a public hearing that is held:
(A)
in accordance with Subsections
(8)
and
(9)
; and
(B)
in conjunction with the public hearing required by Section
17-63-304
or
17B-1-610
.
(b)
(i)
For a county executive calendar year taxing entity, the statement described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
shall be made by the:
(A)
county council;
(B)
county executive; or
(C)
both the county council and county executive.
(ii)
If the county council makes the statement described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
or the county council states a dollar amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that is greater than the amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue previously stated by the county executive in accordance with Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
, the county executive calendar year taxing entity shall:
(A)
make the statement described in Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
14 or more days before the county executive calendar year taxing entity conducts the public hearing under Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
; and
(B)
provide the notice required by Subsection
(3)(a)(iv)
14 or more days before the county executive calendar year taxing entity conducts the public hearing required by Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
.
(c)
The notice described in Subsection
(3)(a)(iv)
:
(i)
shall be mailed to each owner of property:
(A)
within the calendar year taxing entity; and
(B)
listed on the assessment roll;
(ii)
shall be printed on a separate form that:
(A)
is developed by the commission;
(B)
states at the top of the form, in bold upper-case type no smaller than 18 point &quot;NOTICE OF PROPOSED TAX INCREASE&quot;; and
(C)
may be mailed with the notice required by Section
59-2-1317
;
(iii)
shall contain for each property described in Subsection
(3)(c)(i)
:
(A)
the value of the property for the current calendar year;
(B)
the tax on the property for the current calendar year; and
(C)
subject to Subsection
(3)(d)
, for the calendar year for which the calendar year taxing entity seeks to levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate, the estimated tax on the property;
(iv)
shall contain the following statement:
&quot;[Insert name of taxing entity] is proposing a tax increase for [insert applicable calendar year].  This notice contains estimates of the tax on your property and the proposed tax increase on your property as a result of this tax increase.  These estimates are calculated on the basis of [insert previous applicable calendar year] data.  The actual tax on your property and proposed tax increase on your property may vary from this estimate.&quot;;
(v)
shall state the dollar amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that would be generated each year by the proposed increase in the certified tax rate;
(vi)
shall include a brief statement of the primary purpose for the proposed tax increase, including the taxing entity's intended use of additional ad valorem tax revenue described in Subsection
(3)(c)(v)
;
(vii)
shall state the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
;
(viii)
shall state the Internet address for the taxing entity's public website;
(ix)
may contain other information approved by the commission; and
(x)
if sent in calendar year 2024, 2025, or 2026, shall contain:
(A)
notice that the taxpayer may request electronic notice as described in Subsection 17-71-302(1)(m); and
(B)
instructions describing how to elect to receive a notice as described in Subsection
17-71-302(1)(m)
.
(d)
For purposes of Subsection
(3)(c)(iii)(C)
, a calendar year taxing entity shall calculate the estimated tax on property on the basis of:
(i)
data for the current calendar year; and
(ii)
the amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue stated in accordance with this section.
(4)
Except as provided in Subsection
(5)
, a fiscal year taxing entity may levy a tax rate that exceeds the fiscal year taxing entity's certified tax rate if the fiscal year taxing entity:
(a)
provides notice by meeting the advertisement requirements of Subsections
(6)
and
(7)
before the fiscal year taxing entity conducts the public meeting at which the fiscal year taxing entity's annual budget is adopted; and
(b)
conducts a public hearing in accordance with Subsections
(8)
and
(9)
before the fiscal year taxing entity's annual budget is adopted.
(5)
(a)
A taxing entity is not required to meet the notice or public hearing requirements of Subsection
(3)
or
(4)
if the taxing entity is expressly exempted by law from complying with the requirements of this section.
(b)
A taxing entity is not required to meet the notice requirements of Subsection
(3)
or
(4)
if:
(i)
Section
53F-8-301
allows the taxing entity to levy a tax rate that exceeds that certified tax rate without having to comply with the notice provisions of this section; or
(ii)
the taxing entity:
(A)
budgeted less than $20,000 in ad valorem tax revenue for the previous fiscal year; and
(B)
sets a budget during the current fiscal year of less than $20,000 of ad valorem tax revenue.
(6)
(a)
Before holding the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
, a taxing entity proposing a tax rate increase under this section shall publish an advertisement regarding the proposed tax increase:
(i)
electronically in accordance with Section
45-1-101
; and
(ii)
as a class A notice under Section
63G-30-102
.
(b)
The advertisement described in Subsection
(6)(a)
shall:
(i)
be published for at least 14 days before the day on which the taxing entity conducts the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
; and
(ii)
substantially be in the following form and content:
&quot;NOTICE OF PROPOSED TAX INCREASE
(NAME OF TAXING ENTITY)
The (name of the taxing entity) is proposing to increase its property tax revenue.
The (name of the taxing entity) tax on a (insert the average value of a residence in the taxing entity rounded to the nearest thousand dollars) residence would increase from $______ to $________, which is $_______ per year.
The (name of the taxing entity) tax on a (insert the value of a business having the same value as the average value of a residence in the taxing entity) business would increase from $________ to $_______, which is $______ per year.
If the proposed budget is approved, (name of the taxing entity) would receive an additional $______ in property tax revenue per year as a result of the tax increase.
If the proposed budget is approved, (name of the taxing entity) would increase its property tax budgeted revenue by ___% above last year's property tax budgeted revenue excluding eligible new growth.
The (name of the taxing entity) invites all concerned citizens to a public hearing for the purpose of hearing comments regarding the proposed tax increase and to explain the reasons for the proposed tax increase. You have the option to attend or participate in the public hearing in person or online.
PUBLIC HEARING
Date/Time:     (date) (time)
Location:     (name of meeting place and address of meeting place)
Virtual Meeting Link:     (Internet address for remote participation and live streaming options)
To obtain more information regarding the tax increase, citizens may contact the (name of the taxing entity) at (phone number of taxing entity) or visit (Internet address for the taxing entity's public website).&quot;
(7)
The commission:
(a)
shall adopt rules in accordance with Title
63G, Chapter 3
, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, governing the joint use of one advertisement described in Subsection
(6)
by two or more taxing entities; and
(b)
subject to Section
45-1-101
, may authorize a taxing entity's use of a commission-approved direct notice to each taxpayer if:
(i)
the direct notice is different and separate from the notice required under Section
59-2-919.1
; and
(ii)
the taxing entity petitions the commission for the use of a commission-approved direct notice.
(8)
(a)
(i)
On or before June 1, a fiscal year taxing entity shall notify the commission and the county auditor of the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection
(4)(b)
.
(ii)
On or before October 1 of the current calendar year, a calendar year taxing entity shall notify the commission and the county auditor of the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
.
(b)
(i)
A public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
shall be:
(A)
open to the public;
(B)
held at a meeting of the taxing entity with no items on the agenda other than discussion and action on the taxing entity's intent to levy a tax rate that exceeds the taxing entity's certified tax rate, the taxing entity's budget, a special district's or special service district's fee implementation or increase, or a combination of these items; and
(C)
available for individuals to attend or participate either in person or remotely through electronic means.
(ii)
The governing body of a taxing entity conducting a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
shall:
(A)
state the dollar amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that would be generated each year by the proposed increase in the certified tax rate;
(B)
explain the reasons for the proposed tax increase, including the taxing entity's intended use of additional ad valorem tax revenue described in Subsection
(8)(b)(ii)(A)
;
(C)
if the county auditor compiles the list required by Section
59-2-919.2
, present the list at the public hearing and make the list available on the taxing entity's public website; and
(D)
provide an interested party desiring to be heard an opportunity to present oral testimony within reasonable time limits and without unreasonable restriction on the number of individuals allowed to make public comment.
(c)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(8)(c)(ii)
, a taxing entity may not schedule a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
at the same time as the public hearing of another overlapping taxing entity in the same county.
(ii)
The taxing entities in which the power to set tax levies is vested in the same governing board or authority may consolidate the public hearings described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
into one public hearing.
(d)
The county auditor shall resolve any conflict in public hearing dates and times after consultation with each affected taxing entity.
(e)
(i)
A taxing entity shall hold a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
beginning at or after 6 p.m.
(ii)
If a taxing entity holds a public meeting for the purpose of addressing general business of the taxing entity on the same date as a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
, the public meeting addressing general business items shall conclude before the beginning of the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
.
(f)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(8)(f)(ii)
, a taxing entity may not hold the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
on the same date as another public hearing of the taxing entity.
(ii)
A taxing entity may hold the following hearings on the same date as a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
:
(A)
a budget hearing;
(B)
if the taxing entity is a special district or a special service district, a fee hearing described in Section
17B-1-643
;
(C)
if the taxing entity is a town, an enterprise fund hearing described in Section
10-5-107.5
; or
(D)
if the taxing entity is a city, an enterprise fund hearing described in Section
10-6-135.5
.
(9)
(a)
If a taxing entity does not make a final decision on budgeting additional ad valorem tax revenue at a public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
, the taxing entity shall:
(i)
announce at that public hearing the scheduled time and place of the next public meeting at which the taxing entity will consider budgeting the additional ad valorem tax revenue; and
(ii)
if the taxing entity is a fiscal year taxing entity, hold the public meeting described in Subsection
(9)(a)(i)
before September 1.
(b)
A calendar year taxing entity may not adopt a final budget that budgets an amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that exceeds the largest amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue stated at a public meeting under Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
.
(c)
A public hearing on levying a tax rate that exceeds a fiscal year taxing entity's certified tax rate may coincide with a public hearing on the fiscal year taxing entity's proposed annual budget.
(10)
(a)
A county auditor may conduct an audit to verify a taxing entity's compliance with Subsection
(8)
.
(b)
If the county auditor, after completing an audit, finds that a taxing entity has failed to meet the requirements of Subsection
(8)
, the county auditor shall prepare and submit a report of the auditor's findings to the commission.
(c)
The commission may not certify a tax rate that exceeds a taxing entity's certified tax rate if, on or before September 15 of the year in which the taxing entity is required to hold the public hearing described in Subsection
(3)(a)(v)
or
(4)(b)
, the commission determines that the taxing entity has failed to meet the requirements of Subsection
(8)
.
(11)
For a fiscal year within a truth-in-taxation exemption period, a taxing entity may adopt a budget that is equal to or less than the base year budgeted revenue without complying with this section.
Amended by Chapter
17
, 2025 Special Session 1</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Additional ad valorem tax revenue&quot; means ad valorem property tax revenue generated by the portion of the tax rate that exceeds the taxing entity's certified tax rate.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Ad valorem tax revenue&quot; means ad valorem property tax revenue not including revenue from:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>eligible new growth; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>personal property that is:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Base year&quot; means a taxing entity's fiscal year that immediately precedes the fiscal year in which the taxing entity first adopted a budget below last year's property tax budgeted revenue.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Base year budgeted revenue&quot; means the property tax budgeted revenue, excluding eligible new growth, for the base year.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Calendar year taxing entity&quot; means a taxing entity that operates under a fiscal year that begins on January 1 and ends on December 31.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;County executive calendar year taxing entity&quot; means a calendar year taxing entity that operates under the county executive-council form of government described in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Current calendar year&quot; means the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year for which a calendar year taxing entity seeks to levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Eligible new growth&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Fiscal year taxing entity&quot; means a taxing entity that operates under a fiscal year that begins on July 1 and ends on June 30.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Meeting&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Last year's property tax budgeted revenue&quot; does not include:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>revenue received by a taxing entity from a debt service levy voted on by the public;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>revenue generated by the combined basic rate as defined in Section ; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_k__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>revenue generated by the charter school levy described in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_1__para_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Truth-in-taxation exemption period&quot; means a six-year period that begins with the base year.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a taxing entity may not levy a tax rate that exceeds the taxing entity's certified tax rate unless the taxing entity meets:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the requirements of this section that apply to the taxing entity; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>all other requirements as may be required by law.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsection and except as provided in Subsection , a calendar year taxing entity may levy a tax rate that exceeds the calendar year taxing entity's certified tax rate if the calendar year taxing entity:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>14 or more days before the date of the regular general election or municipal general election held in the current calendar year, states at a public meeting:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>provides notice for the public meeting described in Subsection in accordance with Title , Open and Public Meetings Act, including providing a separate item on the meeting agenda that notifies the public that the calendar year taxing entity intends to make the statement described in Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>meets the advertisement requirements of Subsections and before the calendar year taxing entity conducts the public hearing required by Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>provides notice by mail:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>conducts a public hearing that is held:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For a county executive calendar year taxing entity, the statement described in Subsection shall be made by the:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the county council makes the statement described in Subsection or the county council states a dollar amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that is greater than the amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue previously stated by the county executive in accordance with Subsection , the county executive calendar year taxing entity shall:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The notice described in Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall be mailed to each owner of property:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall be printed on a separate form that:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall contain for each property described in Subsection :</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall contain the following statement: &quot;[Insert name of taxing entity] is proposing a tax increase for [insert applicable calendar year].  This notice contains estimates of the tax on your property and the proposed tax increase on your property as a result of this tax increase.  These estimates are calculated on the basis of [insert previous applicable calendar year] data.  The actual tax on your property and proposed tax increase on your property may vary from this estimate.&quot;;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall state the dollar amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that would be generated each year by the proposed increase in the certified tax rate;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_vi">
                <num>(vi)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall include a brief statement of the primary purpose for the proposed tax increase, including the taxing entity's intended use of additional ad valorem tax revenue described in Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_vii">
                <num>(vii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall state the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection ;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_viii">
                <num>(viii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall state the Internet address for the taxing entity's public website;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_ix">
                <num>(ix)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>may contain other information approved by the commission; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_x">
                <num>(x)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>if sent in calendar year 2024, 2025, or 2026, shall contain:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For purposes of Subsection , a calendar year taxing entity shall calculate the estimated tax on property on the basis of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>data for the current calendar year; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_3__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue stated in accordance with this section.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a fiscal year taxing entity may levy a tax rate that exceeds the fiscal year taxing entity's certified tax rate if the fiscal year taxing entity:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>provides notice by meeting the advertisement requirements of Subsections and before the fiscal year taxing entity conducts the public meeting at which the fiscal year taxing entity's annual budget is adopted; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>conducts a public hearing in accordance with Subsections and before the fiscal year taxing entity's annual budget is adopted.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_5__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A taxing entity is not required to meet the notice or public hearing requirements of Subsection or if the taxing entity is expressly exempted by law from complying with the requirements of this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_5__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A taxing entity is not required to meet the notice requirements of Subsection or if:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Section allows the taxing entity to levy a tax rate that exceeds that certified tax rate without having to comply with the notice provisions of this section; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_5__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the taxing entity:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Before holding the public hearing described in Subsection or , a taxing entity proposing a tax rate increase under this section shall publish an advertisement regarding the proposed tax increase:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>electronically in accordance with Section ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>as a class A notice under Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The advertisement described in Subsection shall:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>be published for at least 14 days before the day on which the taxing entity conducts the public hearing described in Subsection or ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_6__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>substantially be in the following form and content: &quot;NOTICE OF PROPOSED TAX INCREASE (NAME OF TAXING ENTITY) The (name of the taxing entity) is proposing to increase its property tax revenue. The (name of the taxing entity) tax on a (insert the average value of a residence in the taxing entity rounded to the nearest thousand dollars) residence would increase from $______ to $________, which is $_______ per year. The (name of the taxing entity) tax on a (insert the value of a business having the same value as the average value of a residence in the taxing entity) business would increase from $________ to $_______, which is $______ per year. If the proposed budget is approved, (name of the taxing entity) would receive an additional $______ in property tax revenue per year as a result of the tax increase. If the proposed budget is approved, (name of the taxing entity) would increase its property tax budgeted revenue by ___% above last year's property tax budgeted revenue excluding eligible new growth. The (name of the taxing entity) invites all concerned citizens to a public hearing for the purpose of hearing comments regarding the proposed tax increase and to explain the reasons for the proposed tax increase. You have the option to attend or participate in the public hearing in person or online. PUBLIC HEARING Date/Time:     (date) (time) Location:     (name of meeting place and address of meeting place) Virtual Meeting Link:     (Internet address for remote participation and live streaming options) To obtain more information regarding the tax increase, citizens may contact the (name of the taxing entity) at (phone number of taxing entity) or visit (Internet address for the taxing entity's public website).&quot;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>The commission:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_7__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>shall adopt rules in accordance with Title , Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, governing the joint use of one advertisement described in Subsection by two or more taxing entities; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_7__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>subject to Section , may authorize a taxing entity's use of a commission-approved direct notice to each taxpayer if:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the direct notice is different and separate from the notice required under Section ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_7__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the taxing entity petitions the commission for the use of a commission-approved direct notice.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>On or before June 1, a fiscal year taxing entity shall notify the commission and the county auditor of the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>On or before October 1 of the current calendar year, a calendar year taxing entity shall notify the commission and the county auditor of the date, time, and place of the public hearing described in Subsection .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A public hearing described in Subsection or shall be:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The governing body of a taxing entity conducting a public hearing described in Subsection or shall:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a taxing entity may not schedule a public hearing described in Subsection or at the same time as the public hearing of another overlapping taxing entity in the same county.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The taxing entities in which the power to set tax levies is vested in the same governing board or authority may consolidate the public hearings described in Subsection or into one public hearing.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The county auditor shall resolve any conflict in public hearing dates and times after consultation with each affected taxing entity.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A taxing entity shall hold a public hearing described in Subsection or beginning at or after 6 p.m.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If a taxing entity holds a public meeting for the purpose of addressing general business of the taxing entity on the same date as a public hearing described in Subsection or , the public meeting addressing general business items shall conclude before the beginning of the public hearing described in Subsection or .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_f__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a taxing entity may not hold the public hearing described in Subsection or on the same date as another public hearing of the taxing entity.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_8__para_f__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A taxing entity may hold the following hearings on the same date as a public hearing described in Subsection or :</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_9">
            <num>(9)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_9__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a taxing entity does not make a final decision on budgeting additional ad valorem tax revenue at a public hearing described in Subsection or , the taxing entity shall:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_9__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>announce at that public hearing the scheduled time and place of the next public meeting at which the taxing entity will consider budgeting the additional ad valorem tax revenue; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_9__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>if the taxing entity is a fiscal year taxing entity, hold the public meeting described in Subsection before September 1.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_9__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A calendar year taxing entity may not adopt a final budget that budgets an amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue that exceeds the largest amount of additional ad valorem tax revenue stated at a public meeting under Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_9__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A public hearing on levying a tax rate that exceeds a fiscal year taxing entity's certified tax rate may coincide with a public hearing on the fiscal year taxing entity's proposed annual budget.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_10">
            <num>(10)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_10__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A county auditor may conduct an audit to verify a taxing entity's compliance with Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_10__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If the county auditor, after completing an audit, finds that a taxing entity has failed to meet the requirements of Subsection , the county auditor shall prepare and submit a report of the auditor's findings to the commission.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_2_919__subsec_10__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission may not certify a tax rate that exceeds a taxing entity's certified tax rate if, on or before September 15 of the year in which the taxing entity is required to hold the public hearing described in Subsection or , the commission determines that the taxing entity has failed to meet the requirements of Subsection .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_2_919__subsec_11">
            <num>(11)</num>
            <content>
              <p>For a fiscal year within a truth-in-taxation exemption period, a taxing entity may adopt a budget that is equal to or less than the base year budgeted revenue without complying with this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
