<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-2-103.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_2">
        <num>Chapter 59-2</num>
        <heading>Property Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_2_103_5">
          <num>59-2-103.5</num>
          <heading>Procedures to obtain an exemption for residential property -- Procedure if property owner or property no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 7/1/2025
59-2-103.5.
Procedures to obtain an exemption for residential property -- Procedure if property owner or property no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption.
(1)
Subject to Subsections
(4)
, (5), (6), and (11), for residential property other than part-year residential property, a county legislative body may adopt an ordinance that requires an owner to file an application with the county board of equalization before the county applies a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
to the value of the residential property if:
(a)
the residential property was ineligible for the residential exemption during the calendar year immediately preceding the calendar year for which the owner is seeking to have the residential exemption applied to the value of the residential property;
(b)
an ownership interest in the residential property changes; or
(c)
the county board of equalization determines that there is reason to believe that the residential property no longer qualifies for the residential exemption.
(2)
(a)
The application described in Subsection
(1)
:
(i)
shall be on a form the commission provides by rule and makes available to the counties;
(ii)
shall be signed by the owner of the residential property; and
(iii)
may not request the sales price of the residential property.
(b)
In accordance with Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, the commission may make rules providing the contents of the form described in Subsection
(2)(a)
.
(c)
For purposes of the application described in Subsection
(1)
, a county may not request information from an owner of a residential property beyond the information in the form provided by the commission under this Subsection
(2)
.
(3)
(a)
Regardless of whether a county legislative body adopts an ordinance described in Subsection
(1)
, before a county may apply a residential exemption to the value of part-year residential property, an owner of the property shall:
(i)
subject to Subsection
(6)
, file the application described in Subsection
(2)(a)
with the county board of equalization; and
(ii)
include as part of the application described in Subsection
(2)(a)
a statement that certifies:
(A)
the date the part-year residential property became residential property;
(B)
that the part-year residential property will be used as residential property for 183 or more consecutive calendar days during the calendar year for which the owner seeks to obtain the residential exemption; and
(C)
that the owner, or a member of the owner's household, may not claim a residential exemption for any property for the calendar year for which the owner seeks to obtain the residential exemption, other than the part-year residential property, or as allowed under Section
59-2-103
with respect to the primary residence or household furnishings, furniture, and equipment of the owner's tenant.
(b)
If an owner files an application under this Subsection
(3)
on or after May 1 of the calendar year for which the owner seeks to obtain the residential exemption, the county board of equalization may require the owner to pay an application fee not to exceed $50.
(4)
Before a county allows residential property described in Subsection
59-2-102(35)(b)(ii)
a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
, an owner of the residential property shall file with the county assessor a written declaration that:
(a)
states under penalty of perjury that, to the best of each owner's knowledge, upon completion of construction or occupancy of the residential property, the residential property will be used for residential purposes as a primary residence;
(b)
is signed by each owner of the residential property; and
(c)
is on a form approved by the commission.
(5)
(a)
Before a county allows residential property described in Subsection
59-2-103(6)(b)
a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
, an owner of the residential property shall file with the county assessor a written declaration that:
(i)
states under penalty of perjury that, to the best of each owner's knowledge, the residential property will be used for residential purposes as a primary residence of a tenant;
(ii)
is signed by each owner of the residential property; and
(iii)
is on a form approved by the commission.
(b)
(i)
(A)
In addition to the declaration, a county assessor may request from an owner a current lease agreement signed by the tenant.
(B)
If the lease agreement is insufficient for a county assessor to make a determination about eligibility for a residential exemption, a county assessor may request a copy of the real estate insurance policy for the property.
(C)
If the real estate insurance policy is insufficient for a county assessor to make a determination about eligibility for a residential exemption, a county assessor may request a copy of a filing from the most recent federal tax return showing that the owner had profit or loss from the residential property as a rental.
(ii)
A county assessor may not request information from an owner's tenant.
(6)
(a)
Except as provided in Subsection
(6)(b)
, the county board of equalization may not accept from a property owner an application to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property owner's primary residence that is filed after the later of:
(i)
September 15 of the calendar year for which the property owner seeks to receive the residential exemption; or
(ii)
the last day of a 45-day period beginning on the day on which the county auditor provides the notice under Section
59-2-919.1
.
(b)
(i)
In accordance with Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act, the commission may make rules providing for circumstances under which the county board of equalization is required to accept a property owner's application for a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
that is filed after the time period described in Subsection
(6)(a)
.
(ii)
The commission shall report to the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee on any rules promulgated under this Subsection
(6)(b)
.
(7)
Except as provided in Subsection
(8)
, if a property owner no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property owner's primary residence, the property owner shall:
(a)
file a written statement with the county board of equalization of the county in which the property is located:
(i)
on a form provided by the county board of equalization; and
(ii)
notifying the county board of equalization that the property owner no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property owner's primary residence; and
(b)
declare on the property owner's individual income tax return under Chapter 10, Individual Income Tax Act, for the taxable year for which the property owner no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property owner's primary residence, that the property owner no longer qualifies to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property owner's primary residence.
(8)
A property owner is not required to file a written statement or make the declaration described in Subsection
(7)
if the property owner:
(a)
changes primary residences;
(b)
qualified to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the residence that was the property owner's former primary residence; and
(c)
qualifies to receive a residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the residence that is the property owner's current primary residence.
(9)
Subsections
(2)
through
(8)
do not apply to qualifying exempt primary residential rental personal property.
(10)
(a)
Subject to Subsection
(11)
, for the first calendar year in which a property owner qualifies to receive a residential exemption under Section
59-2-103
, a county assessor may require the property owner to file a signed statement described in Section
59-2-306
.
(b)
Subject to Subsection
(11)
and notwithstanding Section
59-2-306
, for a calendar year after the calendar year described in Subsection
(10)(a)
in which a property owner qualifies for an exemption authorized under Section
59-2-1115
for qualifying exempt primary residential rental personal property, a signed statement described in Section
59-2-306
with respect to the qualifying exempt primary residential rental personal property may only require the property owner to certify, under penalty of perjury, that the property owner qualifies for the exemption authorized under Section
59-2-1115
.
(11)
(a)
After an ownership interest in residential property changes, the county assessor shall:
(i)
notify the owner of the residential property that the owner is required to submit a written declaration described in Subsection
(11)(d)
within 90 days after the day on which the county assessor mails the notice under this Subsection
(11)(a)
; and
(ii)
provide the owner of the residential property with the form described in Subsection
(11)(e)
to make the written declaration described in Subsection
(11)(d)
.
(b)
A county assessor is not required to provide a notice to an owner of residential property under Subsection
(11)(a)
if the situs address of the residential property is the same as any one of the following:
(i)
the mailing address of the residential property owner or the tenant of the residential property;
(ii)
the address listed on the:
(A)
residential property owner's driver license; or
(B)
tenant of the residential property's driver license; or
(iii)
the address listed on the:
(A)
residential property owner's voter registration; or
(B)
tenant of the residential property's voter registration.
(c)
A county assessor is not required to provide a notice to an owner of residential property under Subsection
(11)(a)
if:
(i)
the owner is using a post office box or rural route box located in the county where the residential property is located; and
(ii)
the residential property is located in a county of the fourth, fifth, or sixth class.
(d)
An owner of residential property that receives a notice described in Subsection
(11)(a)
shall submit a written declaration to the county assessor under penalty of perjury certifying the information contained in the form described in Subsection
(11)(e)
.
(e)
The written declaration required by Subsection
(11)(d)
shall be:
(i)
signed by the owner of the residential property; and
(ii)
in substantially the following form:
&quot;Residential Property Declaration
This form must be submitted to the County Assessor's office where your new residential property is located within 90 days of receipt. Failure to do so will result in the county assessor taking action that could result in the withdrawal of the primary residential exemption from your residential property.
Residential Property Owner Information
Name(s):__________________________________________________
Home Phone:_______________________________________________
Work Phone:_______________________________________________
Mailing Address:____________________________________________
Residential Property Information
Physical Address:___________________________________________
Certification
1.  Is this property used as a primary residential property or part-year residential property for you or another person?
&quot;Part-year residential property&quot; means owned property that is not residential property on January 1 of a calendar year but becomes residential property after January 1 of the calendar year.
Yes           No
2.  Will this primary residential property or part-year residential property be occupied for 183 or more consecutive calendar days by the owner or another person?
A part-year residential property occupied for 183 or more consecutive calendar days in a calendar year by the owner(s) or a tenant is eligible for the exemption.
Yes          No
If a property owner or a property owner's spouse claims a residential exemption under Utah Code Ann. §
59-2-103
for property in this state that is the primary residence of the property owner or the property owner's spouse, that claim of a residential exemption shall be considered in determining whether the property owner and the property owner's spouse have domicile in Utah for income tax purposes.
Signature
Under penalties of perjury, I declare to the best of my knowledge and belief, this declaration and accompanying pages are true, correct, and complete.
__________________(Owner signature) _____________________Date (mm/dd/yyyy)
__________________(Owner printed name)
(f)
For purposes of a written declaration described in this Subsection
(11)
, a county may not request information from a property owner beyond the information described in the form provided in Subsection
(11)(e)
.
(g)
(i)
If, after receiving a written declaration filed under Subsection
(11)(d)
, the county determines that the property has been incorrectly qualified or disqualified to receive a residential exemption, the county shall:
(A)
redetermine the property's qualification to receive a residential exemption; and
(B)
notify the claimant of the redetermination and the county's reason for the redetermination.
(ii)
The redetermination provided in Subsection
(11)(g)(i)(A)
is final unless:
(A)
except as provided in Subsection
(11)(g)(iii)
, the property owner appeals the redetermination to the board of equalization in accordance with Subsection
59-2-1004(2)
; or
(B)
the county determines that the property is eligible to receive a primary residential exemption as part-year residential property.
(iii)
The board of equalization may not accept an appeal that is filed after the later of:
(A)
September 15 of the current calendar year; or
(B)
the last day of the 45-day period beginning on the day on which the county auditor provides the notice under Section
59-2-919.1
.
(h)
(i)
If a residential property owner fails to file a written declaration required by Subsection
(11)(d)
, the county assessor shall mail to the owner of the residential property a notice that:
(A)
the property owner failed to file a written declaration as required by Subsection
(11)(d)
; and
(B)
the property owner will no longer qualify to receive the residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
for the property that is the subject of the written declaration if the property owner does not file the written declaration required by Subsection
(11)(d)
within 30 days after the day on which the county assessor mails the notice under this Subsection
(11)(h)(i)
.
(ii)
If a property owner fails to file a written declaration required by Subsection
(11)(d)
after receiving the notice described in Subsection
(11)(h)(i)
, the property owner no longer qualifies to receive the residential exemption authorized under Section
59-2-103
in the calendar year for the property that is the subject of the written declaration unless:
(A)
except as provided in Subsection
(11)(h)(iii)
, the property owner appeals the redetermination to the board of equalization in accordance with Subsection
59-2-1004(2)
; or
(B)
the county determines that the property is eligible to receive a primary residential exemption as part-year residential property.
(iii)
The board of equalization may not accept an appeal that is filed after the later of:
(A)
September 15 of the current calendar year; or
(B)
the last day of the 45-day period beginning on the day on which the county auditor provides the notice under Section
59-2-919.1
.
(iv)
A property owner that is disqualified to receive the residential exemption under Subsection
(11)(h)(ii)
may file an application described in Subsection
(1)
to determine whether the owner is eligible to receive the residential exemption.
(i)
The requirements of this Subsection
(11)
do not apply to a county assessor in a county that adopts and enforces an ordinance described in Subsection
(1)
.
Amended by Chapter
234
, 2025 General Session</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
