<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-1025/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_10">
        <num>Chapter 59-10</num>
        <heading>Individual Income Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_10_1025">
          <num>59-10-1025</num>
          <heading>Nonrefundable tax credit for investment in certain life science establishments.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 5/7/2025
59-10-1025.
Nonrefundable tax credit for investment in certain life science establishments.
(1)
As used in this section:
(a)
&quot;Commercial domicile&quot; means the principal place from which the trade or business of a Utah small business corporation is directed or managed.
(b)
&quot;Eligible claimant, estate, or trust&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
63N-2-802
.
(c)
&quot;Life science establishment&quot; means an establishment primarily engaged in the development or manufacture of products in one or more of the following categories:
(i)
biotechnologies;
(ii)
medical devices;
(iii)
medical diagnostics; and
(iv)
pharmaceuticals.
(d)
&quot;Office&quot; means the Governor's Office of Economic Opportunity.
(e)
&quot;Pass-through entity&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
59-10-1402
.
(f)
&quot;Pass-through entity taxpayer&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
59-10-1402
.
(g)
&quot;Qualifying ownership interest&quot; means an ownership interest that is:
(i)
(A)
common stock;
(B)
preferred stock; or
(C)
an ownership interest in a pass-through entity;
(ii)
originally issued to:
(A)
an eligible claimant, estate, or trust; or
(B)
a pass-through entity if the eligible claimant, estate, or trust that claims a tax credit under this section was a pass-through entity taxpayer of the pass-through entity on the day on which the qualifying ownership interest was issued and remains a pass-through entity taxpayer of the pass-through entity until the last day of the taxable year for which the eligible claimant, estate, or trust claims a tax credit under this section; and
(iii)
issued:
(A)
by a Utah small business corporation;
(B)
on or after January 1, 2011; and
(C)
for money or other property, except for stock or securities.
(h)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(1)(h)(ii)
, &quot;Utah small business corporation&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section
59-10-1022
.
(ii)
For purposes of this section, a corporation under Section 1244(c)(3)(A), Internal Revenue Code, is considered to include a pass-through entity.
(2)
Subject to the other provisions of this section, an eligible claimant, estate, or trust that holds a tax credit certificate issued to the eligible claimant, estate, or trust in accordance with Section
63N-2-808
for that taxable year may claim a nonrefundable tax credit in an amount up to 35% of the purchase price of a qualifying ownership interest in a Utah small business corporation by the claimant, estate, or trust if:
(a)
the qualifying ownership interest is issued by a Utah small business corporation that is a life science establishment;
(b)
the qualifying ownership interest in the Utah small business corporation is purchased for at least $25,000;
(c)
the eligible claimant, estate, or trust owned less than 30% of the qualifying ownership interest of the Utah small business corporation at the time of the purchase of the qualifying ownership interest; and
(d)
on each day of the taxable year in which the purchase of the qualifying ownership interest was made, the Utah small business corporation described in Subsection
(2)(a)
has at least 50% of its employees in the state.
(3)
Subject to Subsection
(4)
, the tax credit under Subsection
(2)
:
(a)
may only be claimed by an eligible claimant, estate, or trust:
(i)
for a taxable year for which the eligible claimant, estate, or trust holds a tax credit certificate issued in accordance with Section
63N-2-808
; and
(ii)
subject to obtaining a tax credit certificate for each taxable year as required by Subsection
(3)(a)(i)
, for a period of three taxable years as follows:
(A)
the tax credit in the taxable year in which the purchase of the qualifying ownership interest was made may not exceed 10% of the purchase price of the qualifying ownership interest;
(B)
the tax credit in the taxable year after the taxable year described in Subsection
(3)(a)(ii)(A)
may not exceed 10% of the purchase price of the qualifying ownership interest; and
(C)
the tax credit in the taxable year two years after the taxable year described in Subsection
(3)(a)(ii)(A)
may not exceed 15% of the purchase price of the qualifying ownership interest; and
(b)
may not exceed the lesser of:
(i)
the amount listed on the tax credit certificate issued in accordance with Section
63N-2-808
; or
(ii)
$350,000 in a taxable year.
(4)
An eligible claimant, estate, or trust may not claim a tax credit under this section for a taxable year if the eligible claimant, estate, or trust:
(a)
has sold any of the qualifying ownership interest during the taxable year; or
(b)
does not hold a tax credit certificate for that taxable year that is issued to the eligible claimant, estate, or trust by the office in accordance with Section
63N-2-808
.
(5)
If a Utah small business corporation in which an eligible claimant, estate, or trust purchases a qualifying ownership interest fails, dissolves, or otherwise goes out of business, the eligible claimant, estate, or trust may not claim both the tax credit provided in this section and a capital loss on the qualifying ownership interest.
(6)
If an eligible claimant is a pass-through entity taxpayer that files a return under
Chapter 7, Corporate Franchise and Income Taxes
, the eligible claimant may claim the tax credit under this section on the return filed under
Chapter 7, Corporate Franchise and Income Taxes
.
(7)
A claimant, estate, or trust may not carry forward or carry back a tax credit under this section.
(8)
(a)
(i)
To assist the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee with the review required by Section
59-10-137
, the office shall provide the following information, if available to the office, to the Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst by electronic means:
(A)
the amount of tax credit that the office grants to each eligible business entity for each taxable year;
(B)
the amount of eligible new state tax revenues generated by each eligible product or project;
(C)
estimates for each of the next three calendar years of the following:
(I)
the amount of tax credit that the office will grant;
(II)
the amount of eligible new state tax revenues that will be generated; and
(III)
the number of new incremental jobs within the state that will be generated; and
(D)
any other information that the Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst requests.
(ii)
In providing the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i), the office shall redact information that identifies a recipient of a tax credit under this section.
(iii)
If, notwithstanding the redactions made under Subsection (8)(a)(ii), reporting the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i) might disclose the identity of a recipient of a tax credit, the office may file a request with the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee to provide the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i) in the aggregate for all entities that receive the tax credit under this section.
(b)
The Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst shall report to the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee a summary and analysis of the information provided to the Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst by the office under Subsection (8)(a).
Amended by Chapter
292
, 2025 General Session</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Commercial domicile&quot; means the principal place from which the trade or business of a Utah small business corporation is directed or managed.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Eligible claimant, estate, or trust&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Life science establishment&quot; means an establishment primarily engaged in the development or manufacture of products in one or more of the following categories:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>biotechnologies;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>medical devices;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>medical diagnostics; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>pharmaceuticals.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Office&quot; means the Governor's Office of Economic Opportunity.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Pass-through entity&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Pass-through entity taxpayer&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Qualifying ownership interest&quot; means an ownership interest that is:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_g__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_g__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>originally issued to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_g__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>issued:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_h__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , &quot;Utah small business corporation&quot; means the same as that term is defined in Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_1__para_h__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of this section, a corporation under Section 1244(c)(3)(A), Internal Revenue Code, is considered to include a pass-through entity.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to the other provisions of this section, an eligible claimant, estate, or trust that holds a tax credit certificate issued to the eligible claimant, estate, or trust in accordance with Section for that taxable year may claim a nonrefundable tax credit in an amount up to 35% of the purchase price of a qualifying ownership interest in a Utah small business corporation by the claimant, estate, or trust if:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the qualifying ownership interest is issued by a Utah small business corporation that is a life science establishment;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the qualifying ownership interest in the Utah small business corporation is purchased for at least $25,000;</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>the eligible claimant, estate, or trust owned less than 30% of the qualifying ownership interest of the Utah small business corporation at the time of the purchase of the qualifying ownership interest; and</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_2__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>on each day of the taxable year in which the purchase of the qualifying ownership interest was made, the Utah small business corporation described in Subsection has at least 50% of its employees in the state.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <content>
              <p>Subject to Subsection , the tax credit under Subsection :</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>may only be claimed by an eligible claimant, estate, or trust:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>for a taxable year for which the eligible claimant, estate, or trust holds a tax credit certificate issued in accordance with Section ; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>subject to obtaining a tax credit certificate for each taxable year as required by Subsection , for a period of three taxable years as follows:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>may not exceed the lesser of:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>the amount listed on the tax credit certificate issued in accordance with Section ; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>$350,000 in a taxable year.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>An eligible claimant, estate, or trust may not claim a tax credit under this section for a taxable year if the eligible claimant, estate, or trust:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_4__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>has sold any of the qualifying ownership interest during the taxable year; or</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_4__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>does not hold a tax credit certificate for that taxable year that is issued to the eligible claimant, estate, or trust by the office in accordance with Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_5">
            <num>(5)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If a Utah small business corporation in which an eligible claimant, estate, or trust purchases a qualifying ownership interest fails, dissolves, or otherwise goes out of business, the eligible claimant, estate, or trust may not claim both the tax credit provided in this section and a capital loss on the qualifying ownership interest.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_6">
            <num>(6)</num>
            <content>
              <p>If an eligible claimant is a pass-through entity taxpayer that files a return under , the eligible claimant may claim the tax credit under this section on the return filed under .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_7">
            <num>(7)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A claimant, estate, or trust may not carry forward or carry back a tax credit under this section.</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8">
            <num>(8)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>To assist the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee with the review required by Section , the office shall provide the following information, if available to the office, to the Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst by electronic means:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>In providing the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i), the office shall redact information that identifies a recipient of a tax credit under this section.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8__para_a__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If, notwithstanding the redactions made under Subsection (8)(a)(ii), reporting the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i) might disclose the identity of a recipient of a tax credit, the office may file a request with the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee to provide the information described in Subsection (8)(a)(i) in the aggregate for all entities that receive the tax credit under this section.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_10_1025__subsec_8__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst shall report to the Revenue and Taxation Interim Committee a summary and analysis of the information provided to the Office of the Legislative Fiscal Analyst by the office under Subsection (8)(a).</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
