<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-12-106/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_12">
        <num>Chapter 59-12</num>
        <heading>Sales and Use Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_12_106">
          <num>59-12-106</num>
          <heading>Definitions -- Sales and use tax license requirements -- Penalty -- Application process and requirements -- No fee -- Bonds -- Presumption of taxability -- Exemption certificates -- Exemption certificate license number to accompany contract bids.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 5/3/2023
59-12-106.
Definitions -- Sales and use tax license requirements -- Penalty -- Application process and requirements -- No fee -- Bonds -- Presumption of taxability -- Exemption certificates -- Exemption certificate license number to accompany contract bids.
(1)
As used in this section:
(a)
&quot;Applicant&quot; means a person that:
(i)
is required by this section to obtain a license; and
(ii)
submits an application:
(A)
to the commission; and
(B)
for a license under this section.
(b)
&quot;Application&quot; means an application for a license under this section.
(c)
&quot;Fiduciary of the applicant&quot; means a person that:
(i)
is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter for an applicant; and
(ii)
(A)
is a corporate officer of the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
;
(B)
is a director of the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
;
(C)
is an employee of the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
;
(D)
is a partner of the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
;
(E)
is a trustee of the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
; or
(F)
has a relationship to the applicant described in Subsection
(1)(c)(i)
that is similar to a relationship described in Subsections
(1)(c)(ii)(A)
through
(E)
as determined by the commission by rule made in accordance with
Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act
.
(d)
&quot;Fiduciary of the licensee&quot; means a person that:
(i)
is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter for a licensee; and
(ii)
(A)
is a corporate officer of the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
;
(B)
is a director of the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
;
(C)
is an employee of the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
;
(D)
is a partner of the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
;
(E)
is a trustee of the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
; or
(F)
has a relationship to the licensee described in Subsection
(1)(d)(i)
that is similar to a relationship described in Subsections
(1)(d)(ii)(A)
through
(E)
as determined by the commission by rule made in accordance with
Title 63G, Chapter 3, Utah Administrative Rulemaking Act
.
(e)
&quot;License&quot; means a license under this section.
(f)
&quot;Licensee&quot; means a person that is licensed under this section by the commission.
(g)
&quot;Special event&quot; means an event that lasts six months or less where taxable sales occur.
(2)
(a)
It is unlawful for any person required to collect a tax under this chapter to engage in business within the state without first having obtained a license to do so.
(b)
The license described in Subsection
(2)(a)
:
(i)
shall be granted and issued by the commission;
(ii)
is not assignable;
(iii)
is valid only for the person in whose name the license is issued;
(iv)
is valid until:
(A)
the person described in Subsection
(2)(b)(iii)
:
(I)
ceases to do business; or
(II)
changes that person's business address; or
(B)
the license is revoked by the commission; and
(v)
subject to Subsection
(2)(d)
, shall be granted by the commission only upon an application that:
(A)
states the name and address of the applicant; and
(B)
provides other information the commission may require.
(c)
At the time an applicant makes an application under Subsection
(2)(b)(v)
, the commission shall notify the applicant of the responsibilities and liability of a business owner successor under Section
59-12-112
.
(d)
The commission shall review an application and determine whether the applicant:
(i)
meets the requirements of this section to be issued a license; and
(ii)
is required to post a bond with the commission in accordance with Subsections
(2)(e)
and
(f)
before the applicant may be issued a license.
(e)
(i)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(e)(iii)
, an applicant shall post a bond with the commission before the commission may issue the applicant a license if:
(A)
a license under this section was revoked for a delinquency under this chapter for:
(I)
the applicant;
(II)
a fiduciary of the applicant; or
(III)
a person for which the applicant or the fiduciary of the applicant is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter; or
(B)
there is a delinquency in paying a tax under this chapter for:
(I)
the applicant;
(II)
a fiduciary of the applicant; or
(III)
a person for which the applicant or the fiduciary of the applicant is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter.
(ii)
If the commission determines it is necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter, the commission may require a licensee to:
(A)
for a licensee that has not posted a bond under this section with the commission, post a bond with the commission in accordance with Subsection
(2)(f)
; or
(B)
for a licensee that has posted a bond under this section with the commission, increase the amount of the bond posted with the commission.
(iii)
The commission may waive the bond requirement described in Subsection
(2)(e)(i)
, if the applicant is in compliance with a payment agreement that:
(A)
relates to the delinquency; and
(B)
is approved by the commission.
(f)
(i)
A bond required by Subsection
(2)(e)
shall be:
(A)
executed by:
(I)
for an applicant, the applicant as principal, with a corporate surety; or
(II)
for a licensee, the licensee as principal, with a corporate surety; and
(B)
payable to the commission conditioned upon the faithful performance of all of the requirements of this chapter including:
(I)
the payment of any tax under this chapter;
(II)
the payment of any:
(Aa)
penalty as provided in Section
59-1-401
; or
(Bb)
interest as provided in Section
59-1-402
; or
(III)
any other obligation of the:
(Aa)
applicant under this chapter; or
(Bb)
licensee under this chapter.
(ii)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(f)(iv)
, the commission shall calculate the amount of a bond required by Subsection
(2)(e)
on the basis of:
(A)
commission estimates of:
(I)
an applicant's tax liability under this chapter; or
(II)
a licensee's tax liability under this chapter; and
(B)
any amount of a delinquency described in Subsection
(2)(f)(iii)
.
(iii)
Except as provided in Subsection
(2)(f)(iv)
, for purposes of Subsection
(2)(f)(ii)(B)
:
(A)
for an applicant, the amount of the delinquency is the sum of:
(I)
the amount of any delinquency that served as a basis for revoking the license under this section of:
(Aa)
the applicant;
(Bb)
a fiduciary of the applicant; or
(Cc)
a person for which the applicant or the fiduciary of the applicant is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter; or
(II)
the amount of tax that any of the following owe under this chapter:
(Aa)
the applicant;
(Bb)
a fiduciary of the applicant; and
(Cc)
a person for which the applicant or the fiduciary of the applicant is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter; or
(B)
for a licensee, the amount of the delinquency is the sum of:
(I)
the amount of any delinquency that served as a basis for revoking the license under this section of:
(Aa)
the licensee;
(Bb)
a fiduciary of the licensee; or
(Cc)
a person for which the licensee or the fiduciary of the licensee is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter; or
(II)
the amount of tax that any of the following owe under this chapter:
(Aa)
the licensee;
(Bb)
a fiduciary of the licensee; and
(Cc)
a person for which the licensee or the fiduciary of the licensee is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter.
(iv)
Notwithstanding Subsection
(2)(f)(ii)
or
(2)(f)(iii)
, a bond required by Subsection
(2)(e)
may not:
(A)
be less than $25,000; or
(B)
exceed $500,000.
(g)
Subject to Subsection
(2)(h)
, if business is transacted at two or more separate places by one person, a separate license for each place of business is required.
(h)
A license is not required for any person:
(i)
engaged exclusively in the business of selling commodities that are exempt from taxation under this chapter; or
(ii)
exempt from collecting sales and use tax under Section
59-12-104
and the place of business is a special event.
(i)
If a person is not required to obtain a license under Subsection
(2)(h)
, a political subdivision, as defined in Subsection
63A-15-102(5)
, may not require the person to obtain a license as a prerequisite to obtaining a business license or any other right to conduct business.
(j)
(i)
The commission shall, on a reasonable notice and after a hearing, revoke the license of any licensee violating any provisions of this chapter.
(ii)
A license may not be issued to a licensee described in Subsection
(2)(j)(i)
until the licensee has complied with the requirements of this chapter, including:
(A)
paying any:
(I)
tax due under this chapter;
(II)
penalty as provided in Section
59-1-401
; or
(III)
interest as provided in Section
59-1-402
; and
(B)
posting a bond in accordance with Subsections
(2)(e)
and
(f)
.
(k)
Any person required to collect a tax under this chapter within this state without having secured a license to do so is guilty of a criminal violation as provided in Section
59-1-401
.
(l)
A license shall be issued to the person by the commission without a license fee.
(m)
(i)
The commission shall include on an application for a temporary sales tax license and special event sales tax return the following statement:
&quot;You are not required to complete or return this form or to collect sales and use tax if you are not regularly engaged in the business of selling the items you are offering at this event or all of the items that you are selling at this event are exempt from sales and use tax under Section
59-12-104
.&quot;
(ii)
The notice described in Subsection
(2)(m)(i)
shall be in bold font no smaller than the font of the main content and shall appear at the top of the application form.
(3)
(a)
For the purpose of the proper administration of this chapter and to prevent evasion of the tax and the duty to collect the tax, it shall be presumed that tangible personal property or any other taxable transaction under Subsection
59-12-103(1)
sold by any person for delivery in this state is sold for storage, use, or other consumption in this state unless the person selling the property, item, or service has taken from the purchaser an exemption certificate:
(i)
bearing the name and address of the purchaser; and
(ii)
providing that the property, item, or service was exempted under Section
59-12-104
.
(b)
An exemption certificate described in Subsection
(3)(a)
:
(i)
shall contain information as prescribed by the commission; and
(ii)
if a paper exemption certificate is used, shall be signed by the purchaser.
(c)
(i)
Subject to Subsection
(3)(c)(ii)
, a seller or certified service provider is not liable to collect a tax under this chapter if the seller or certified service provider obtains within 90 days after a transaction is complete:
(A)
an exemption certificate containing the information required by Subsections
(3)(a)
and
(b)
; or
(B)
the information required by Subsections
(3)(a)
and
(b)
.
(ii)
A seller or certified service provider that does not obtain the exemption certificate or information described in Subsection
(3)(c)(i)
with respect to a transaction is allowed 120 days after the commission requests the seller or certified service provider to substantiate the exemption to:
(A)
establish that the transaction is not subject to taxation under this chapter by a means other than providing an exemption certificate containing the information required by Subsections
(3)(a)
and
(b)
; or
(B)
subject to Subsection
(3)(c)(iii)
, obtain an exemption certificate containing the information required by Subsections
(3)(a)
and
(b)
, taken in good faith.
(iii)
For purposes of Subsection
(3)(c)(ii)(B)
, an exemption certificate is taken in good faith if the exemption certificate claims an exemption that:
(A)
was allowed by statute on the date of the transaction in the jurisdiction of the location of the transaction;
(B)
could be applicable to that transaction; and
(C)
is reasonable for the purchaser's type of business.
(d)
Except as provided in Subsection
(3)(e)
, a seller or certified service provider that takes an exemption certificate from a purchaser in accordance with this Subsection
(3)
with respect to a transaction is not liable to collect a tax under this chapter on that transaction.
(e)
Subsection
(3)(d)
does not apply to a seller or certified service provider if the commission establishes through an audit that the seller or certified service provider:
(i)
knew or had reason to know at the time the purchaser provided the seller or certified service provider the information described in Subsection
(3)(a)
or
(b)
that the information related to the exemption claimed was materially false; or
(ii)
otherwise knowingly participated in activity intended to purposefully evade the tax due on the transaction.
(f)
(i)
Subject to Subsection
(3)(f)(ii)
and except as provided in Subsections
(3)(f)(iii)
and
(iv)
, if there is a recurring business relationship between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser, the commission may not require the seller or certified service provider to:
(A)
renew an exemption certificate;
(B)
update an exemption certificate; or
(C)
update a data element of an exemption certificate.
(ii)
For purposes of Subsection
(3)(f)(i)
, a recurring business relationship exists if no more than a 12-month period elapses between transactions between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser.
(iii)
Notwithstanding any other provision of this Subsection, the commission shall require a seller to renew an exemption certificate if more than 12-months have elapsed between transactions between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser.
(iv)
If there is a recurring business relationship between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser, the commission shall require an exemption certificate the seller or certified service provider takes from the purchaser to meet the requirements of Subsections
(3)(a)
and
(b)
.
(4)
A person filing a contract bid with the state or a political subdivision of the state for the sale of tangible personal property or any other taxable transaction under Subsection
59-12-103(1)
shall include with the bid the number of the license issued to that person under Subsection
(2)
.
Amended by Chapter
83
, 2023 General Session
Amended by Chapter
355
, 2023 General Session</p>
          </content>
          <subsection eId="59_12_106__subsec_1">
            <num>(1)</num>
            <content>
              <p>As used in this section:</p>
            </content>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Applicant&quot; means a person that:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is required by this section to obtain a license; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>submits an application:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Application&quot; means an application for a license under this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Fiduciary of the applicant&quot; means a person that:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter for an applicant; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Fiduciary of the licensee&quot; means a person that:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is required to collect, truthfully account for, and pay over a tax under this chapter for a licensee; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;License&quot; means a license under this section.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Licensee&quot; means a person that is licensed under this section by the commission.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_1__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>&quot;Special event&quot; means an event that lasts six months or less where taxable sales occur.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_106__subsec_2">
            <num>(2)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>It is unlawful for any person required to collect a tax under this chapter to engage in business within the state without first having obtained a license to do so.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The license described in Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall be granted and issued by the commission;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is not assignable;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is valid only for the person in whose name the license is issued;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is valid until:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_b__subpara_v">
                <num>(v)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>subject to Subsection , shall be granted by the commission only upon an application that:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <content>
                <p>At the time an applicant makes an application under Subsection , the commission shall notify the applicant of the responsibilities and liability of a business owner successor under Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>The commission shall review an application and determine whether the applicant:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_d__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>meets the requirements of this section to be issued a license; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_d__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>is required to post a bond with the commission in accordance with Subsections and before the applicant may be issued a license.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , an applicant shall post a bond with the commission before the commission may issue the applicant a license if:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If the commission determines it is necessary to ensure compliance with this chapter, the commission may require a licensee to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_e__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission may waive the bond requirement described in Subsection , if the applicant is in compliance with a payment agreement that:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A bond required by Subsection shall be:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , the commission shall calculate the amount of a bond required by Subsection on the basis of:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Except as provided in Subsection , for purposes of Subsection :</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_f__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding Subsection or , a bond required by Subsection may not:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_g">
              <num>(g)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subject to Subsection , if business is transacted at two or more separate places by one person, a separate license for each place of business is required.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_h">
              <num>(h)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A license is not required for any person:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_h__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>engaged exclusively in the business of selling commodities that are exempt from taxation under this chapter; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_h__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>exempt from collecting sales and use tax under Section and the place of business is a special event.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_i">
              <num>(i)</num>
              <content>
                <p>If a person is not required to obtain a license under Subsection , a political subdivision, as defined in Subsection , may not require the person to obtain a license as a prerequisite to obtaining a business license or any other right to conduct business.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_j">
              <num>(j)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_j__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall, on a reasonable notice and after a hearing, revoke the license of any licensee violating any provisions of this chapter.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_j__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A license may not be issued to a licensee described in Subsection until the licensee has complied with the requirements of this chapter, including:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_k">
              <num>(k)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Any person required to collect a tax under this chapter within this state without having secured a license to do so is guilty of a criminal violation as provided in Section .</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_l">
              <num>(l)</num>
              <content>
                <p>A license shall be issued to the person by the commission without a license fee.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_m">
              <num>(m)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_m__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The commission shall include on an application for a temporary sales tax license and special event sales tax return the following statement: &quot;You are not required to complete or return this form or to collect sales and use tax if you are not regularly engaged in the business of selling the items you are offering at this event or all of the items that you are selling at this event are exempt from sales and use tax under Section .&quot;</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_2__para_m__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>The notice described in Subsection shall be in bold font no smaller than the font of the main content and shall appear at the top of the application form.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_106__subsec_3">
            <num>(3)</num>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_a">
              <num>(a)</num>
              <content>
                <p>For the purpose of the proper administration of this chapter and to prevent evasion of the tax and the duty to collect the tax, it shall be presumed that tangible personal property or any other taxable transaction under Subsection sold by any person for delivery in this state is sold for storage, use, or other consumption in this state unless the person selling the property, item, or service has taken from the purchaser an exemption certificate:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>bearing the name and address of the purchaser; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_a__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>providing that the property, item, or service was exempted under Section .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_b">
              <num>(b)</num>
              <content>
                <p>An exemption certificate described in Subsection :</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>shall contain information as prescribed by the commission; and</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_b__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>if a paper exemption certificate is used, shall be signed by the purchaser.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_c">
              <num>(c)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsection , a seller or certified service provider is not liable to collect a tax under this chapter if the seller or certified service provider obtains within 90 days after a transaction is complete:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>A seller or certified service provider that does not obtain the exemption certificate or information described in Subsection with respect to a transaction is allowed 120 days after the commission requests the seller or certified service provider to substantiate the exemption to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_c__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of Subsection , an exemption certificate is taken in good faith if the exemption certificate claims an exemption that:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_d">
              <num>(d)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Except as provided in Subsection , a seller or certified service provider that takes an exemption certificate from a purchaser in accordance with this Subsection with respect to a transaction is not liable to collect a tax under this chapter on that transaction.</p>
              </content>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_e">
              <num>(e)</num>
              <content>
                <p>Subsection does not apply to a seller or certified service provider if the commission establishes through an audit that the seller or certified service provider:</p>
              </content>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_e__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>knew or had reason to know at the time the purchaser provided the seller or certified service provider the information described in Subsection or that the information related to the exemption claimed was materially false; or</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_e__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>otherwise knowingly participated in activity intended to purposefully evade the tax due on the transaction.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
            <paragraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_f">
              <num>(f)</num>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_f__subpara_i">
                <num>(i)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Subject to Subsection and except as provided in Subsections and , if there is a recurring business relationship between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser, the commission may not require the seller or certified service provider to:</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_f__subpara_ii">
                <num>(ii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>For purposes of Subsection , a recurring business relationship exists if no more than a 12-month period elapses between transactions between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_f__subpara_iii">
                <num>(iii)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Subsection, the commission shall require a seller to renew an exemption certificate if more than 12-months have elapsed between transactions between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser.</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
              <subparagraph eId="59_12_106__subsec_3__para_f__subpara_iv">
                <num>(iv)</num>
                <content>
                  <p>If there is a recurring business relationship between a seller or certified service provider and a purchaser, the commission shall require an exemption certificate the seller or certified service provider takes from the purchaser to meet the requirements of Subsections and .</p>
                </content>
              </subparagraph>
            </paragraph>
          </subsection>
          <subsection eId="59_12_106__subsec_4">
            <num>(4)</num>
            <content>
              <p>A person filing a contract bid with the state or a political subdivision of the state for the sale of tangible personal property or any other taxable transaction under Subsection shall include with the bid the number of the license issued to that person under Subsection .</p>
            </content>
          </subsection>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
