<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<akomaNtoso xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <act name="section">
    <meta>
      <identification source="#ut-legislature">
        <FRBRWork>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="enacted"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRcountry value="us-ut"/>
        </FRBRWork>
        <FRBRExpression>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5/eng"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="publication"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#ut-legislature"/>
          <FRBRlanguage language="eng"/>
        </FRBRExpression>
        <FRBRManifestation>
          <FRBRthis value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRuri value="/us-ut/act/code/59-10-117.5/eng/akn"/>
          <FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation"/>
          <FRBRauthor href="#cosilico"/>
        </FRBRManifestation>
      </identification>
      <references source="#cosilico">
        <TLCOrganization eId="ut-legislature" href="/ontology/organization/us-ut/legislature" showAs="Utah State Legislature"/>
        <TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico"/>
      </references>
    </meta>
    <body>
      <chapter eId="chp_59_10">
        <num>Chapter 59-10</num>
        <heading>Individual Income Tax Act</heading>
        <section eId="sec_59_10_117_5">
          <num>59-10-117.5</num>
          <heading>Nonresident individual wage exemption.</heading>
          <content>
            <p>Effective 1/1/2023
59-10-117.5.
Nonresident individual wage exemption.
(1)
As used in this section:
(a)
&quot;Day&quot; means any period of time during a calendar day that an individual is present in the state, unless the presence is solely for transportation through the state.
(b)
&quot;Wages&quot; means income that:
(i)
is received by an individual for employment duties performed inside this state; and
(ii)
would be subject to withholding in accordance with Section
59-10-402
without regard to Subsection
59-10-402(5)(a)
.
(2)
A nonresident individual's wages may not be considered income derived from Utah sources if:
(a)
the nonresident individual has no other income from sources within this state for the taxable year in which the nonresident individual receives the wages;
(b)
the nonresident individual is present in this state to perform employment duties for 20 or fewer days during the tax year; and
(c)
the nonresident individual's state of residence:
(i)
provides a substantially similar exclusion; or
(ii)
does not impose a state individual income tax.
(3)
This section does not apply to wages received by:
(a)
an individual who is a professional athlete or a member of a professional athletic team;
(b)
an individual who is a professional entertainer and who performs services in the professional performing arts;
(c)
an individual of prominence who performs services for wages on a per-event basis;
(d)
an individual who performs construction services to improve real property, predominantly on a construction site, as a laborer;
(e)
an individual who is a key employee, without regard to ownership or the existence of a benefit plan, for the year immediately preceding the current tax year pursuant to Subsection 416(i), Internal Revenue Code; or
(f)
an individual who is an employee of a non-corporate employer, and who would be a key employee without regard to ownership or the existence of a benefit plan, for the year immediately preceding the current tax year pursuant to Subsection 416(i), Internal Revenue Code, if:
(i)
the term &quot;employee&quot; were substituted for the term &quot;officer&quot;; and
(ii)
the individual is one of the non-corporate employer's 50 highest paid employees without regard to whether the individual is an officer.
Enacted by Chapter
252
, 2022 General Session</p>
          </content>
        </section>
      </chapter>
    </body>
  </act>
</akomaNtoso>
